<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New Releases on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/releases/</link><description>Recent content in New Releases on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2.7.14 Release Note</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/09/20/2.7.14-release-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/09/20/2.7.14-release-note/</guid><description>Change Lists add Dynamic Configuration Override Support For ServiceDiscovery. (#8389) fix mock parameters doesn&amp;rsquo;t work when it contain &amp;lsquo;:&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo;. (#8379) fix the issue of taking the zone parameter value in ZoneAwareClusterInvoker. (#8521) add the switch for check class is in serialize white list , default is true. (#8537) fix NPE on serialization checking when request timed out. (#8587) fix NetUtils.ignoreNetworkInterface can&amp;rsquo;t process network card name contains &amp;lsquo;(&amp;rsquo; symbol. (#8629) unify the way of getting local address.</description></item><item><title>3.0.2.1 Release Note</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/08/23/3.0.2.1-release-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/08/23/3.0.2.1-release-note/</guid><description>This is a bugfix version of 3.0.2. Exactly the same as version 3.0.2, except for the following changes.
Bugfix Fix nacos group inviable in consumer side (#8533) Fix NPE on serialization checking when request timed out (#8547) Compact with dubbo-all without farbic-io (#8546)</description></item><item><title>3.0.2 Release Note</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/08/18/3.0.2-release-note/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/08/18/3.0.2-release-note/</guid><description>Features improve generic service with @DubboService annotation. metadata report config support xml to config protocol and port. compatible for curator5. p2p invoke support wildcard url match. add Dynamic Configuration Override Support For ServiceDiscovery. add provider configuration override disable option. support native image. support disable shutdown hook. add Kubernetes Mesh Rule support. support SSL at netty transport. BugFixs fix re-start override dynamic config. fix delete configurators does not take effect. fix triple protocol will throw exception when the service is exposed.</description></item><item><title>3.0.1 Release Note</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/07/02/3.0.1-release-note/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/07/02/3.0.1-release-note/</guid><description>Optimization Refactor NameMapping to Metadata, Support application field in MigrationRule Add cache for scan result Improve config overrides of method and argument Support servlet takeover mode Add ServiceListener for ServiceConfig Improve method callback BugFixs Add force check Fix multi-registry will destroy unavailable clusters Remove needless toString convert &amp;amp; Enable checking by default Ignore invalid MetadataReportConfig Fix NPE when consumer start Fix some compatiable issues Optimize Service related issues Opt Migration &amp;amp; Fix reSubscribe for ServiceDiscovery Fix NPE in MetadataInfo Fix customizer not changed Code Improvement Thanks for these contribution to improve stability of Apache Dubbo.</description></item><item><title>Past Releases</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2020/05/18/past-releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2020/05/18/past-releases/</guid><description>This document is no longer maintained. You are currently viewing a snapshot version. If you want to see the latest version of the documentation, see Latest Version.
Verification you can follow these procedures and the KEYS file to verify the download files
Apache Dubbo GitHub: https://github.com/apache/dubbo Release Notes: https://github.com/apache/dubbo/releases
3.2.0-beta.3 (2022-12-22) source | asc | sha512 3.1.3 (2022-12-22) source | asc | sha512 2.7.19 (2022-12-13) source | asc | sha512 3.</description></item></channel></rss>