<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Triple Protocol on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/</link><description>Recent content in Triple Protocol on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Protocol Overview</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/overview/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="triple-overview">Triple overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the format and principle of the &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> protocol, please refer to &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docs/concepts/rpc-protocol/">RPC Communication Protocol&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to the goal of Triple design, the &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> protocol has the following advantages&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Capable of cross-language interaction. Both the traditional multi-language and multi-SDK mode and the Mesh cross-language mode require a more general and scalable data transmission protocol.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide a more complete request model. In addition to supporting the traditional Request/Response model (Unary one-way communication), it also supports Stream (streaming communication) and Bidirectional (two-way communication).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy to expand, high penetration, including but not limited to Tracing / Monitoring and other support, should also be recognized by devices at all levels, gateway facilities, etc. can identify data packets, friendly to Service Mesh deployment, and reduce the difficulty of understanding for users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fully compatible with grpc, the client/server can communicate with the native grpc client.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Components in the existing grpc ecosystem can be reused to meet cross-language, cross-environment, and cross-platform intercommunication requirements in cloud-native scenarios.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For Dubbo users currently using other protocols, the framework provides migration capabilities compatible with existing serialization methods. Without affecting existing online businesses, the cost of migrating protocols is almost zero.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instructions for Use</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Triple protocol is the main protocol of Dubbo3, fully compatible with gRPC over HTTP/2, and has expanded load balancing and flow control related mechanisms at the protocol level. This document is intended to guide users to use the Triple protocol correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before starting, you need to decide the serialization method used by the service. If it is a new service, it is recommended to use protobuf as the default serialization, which will have better performance and cross-language effects. If the original service wants to upgrade the protocol, the Triple protocol already supports other serialization methods, such as Hessian / JSON, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>POJO way to use Triple</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/pojo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/pojo/</guid><description>&lt;p>This tutorial will demonstrate how to use Dubbo Triple based on POJO by building a simple project from scratch, and upgrade to the Triple protocol while the application does not change the existing interface definition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="implementation-principle">Implementation principle&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Through the upgrade process described above, we can easily complete the upgrade by modifying the protocol type. How does the framework help us do this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the introduction of the &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> protocol, we know that the data type of &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> in Dubbo3 is a &lt;code>protobuf&lt;/code> object, so why non-&lt;code>protobuf&lt;/code> java objects can also be transmitted normally.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Triple in IDL</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/idl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/idl/</guid><description>&lt;p>This tutorial will demonstrate how to use Dubbo Triple based on IDL by building a simple project from scratch&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="precondition">precondition&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://jdk.java.net/">JDK&lt;/a> version &amp;gt;= 8&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Installed &lt;a href="https://maven.apache.org/">Maven&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Installed and started &lt;a href="https://zookeeper.apache.org/">Zookeeper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="create-project">Create project&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-create-an-empty-maven-project">1. Create an empty maven project&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$ mvn archetype:generate \
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -DgroupId=org.apache.dubbo\
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -DartifactId=tri-stub-demo \
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -DarchetypeArtifactId=maven-archetype-quickstart \
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -DarchetypeVersion=1.4 \
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -DarchetypeGroupId=org.apache.maven.archetypes \
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> -Dversion=1.0-SNAPSHOT
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="2-switch-to-the-project-directory">2. Switch to the project directory&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> $ cd tri-stub-demo
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="3-add-dubbo-dependencies-and-plugins">3. Add Dubbo dependencies and plugins&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Set JDK version in &lt;code>pom.xml&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo2 Protocol Migration</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/migration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dubbo2-protocol-migration-process">Dubbo2 protocol migration process&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dubbo2 users use dubbo protocol + custom serialization, such as hessian2 to complete remote calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, Grpc only supports Protobuf serialization, and it cannot support multi-parameter and method overloading in the Java language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning of Dubbo3, one goal was to be perfectly compatible with Dubbo2. Therefore, in order to ensure the smooth upgrade of Dubbo2, the Dubbo framework has done a lot of work to ensure that the upgrade is seamless. Currently, the default serialization is consistent with Dubbo2 as &lt;code>hessian2&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Streaming Communication</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/streaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/reference-manual/protocol/triple/streaming/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="implementation-principle-of-stream">Implementation principle of stream&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Stream mode for the &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> protocol&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the perspective of the protocol layer, &lt;code>Triple&lt;/code> is built on the basis of &lt;code>HTTP2&lt;/code>, so it directly has all the capabilities of &lt;code>HTTP2&lt;/code>, so it has the ability to split &lt;code>stream&lt;/code> and full-duplex.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In terms of the framework layer, &lt;code>StreamObserver&lt;/code> is provided to users as a stream interface to provide stream processing for input and output parameters. The framework makes corresponding interface calls when sending and receiving stream data, so as to ensure the integrity of the life cycle of the stream.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>