<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What is Dubbo on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/</link><description>Recent content in What is Dubbo on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/overview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an RPC service development framework, which is used to solve service governance and communication problems under the microservice architecture. It officially provides multi-language SDK implementations such as Java and Golang. Microservices developed using Dubbo are natively capable of remote address discovery and communication with each other.
Using the rich service governance features provided by Dubbo, service governance demands such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic scheduling can be realized. Dubbo is designed to be highly scalable, and users can easily implement various custom logics for traffic interception and location selection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo 3 Quick Facts</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/dubbo3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/dubbo3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article will take you to quickly understand the design background, overall architecture and core features of Dubbo3, and its relationship with typical users such as Alibaba HSF2, etc. You can also learn more in the following sections:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New users, take a quick look at the core features of Dubbo3:&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/concepts-and-architecture/triple/">Next Generation Communication Protocol - Triple&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/concepts-and-architecture/service-discovery/">Secrets of a million-instance cluster - application-level service discovery&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/concepts-and-architecture/mesh/">Dubbo Mesh&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dubbo3 compatibility and migration cost?&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/upgrades-and-compatibility">Java - Migration Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/">Golang - Migration Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dubbo3 related resources:&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For more information, such as performance indicators, advanced feature descriptions, etc., please refer to &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/">Multilingual SDK Implementation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speeches and offline activities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="background">background&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The design and development of Dubbo3 has two major backgrounds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/architecture/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="rpc-communication">RPC communication&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dubbo3&amp;rsquo;s Triple protocol is built on the HTTP/2 protocol, so it has better penetration and versatility. The Triple protocol is compatible with gRPC and provides communication models such as Request Response, Request Streaming, Response Streaming, and Bi-directional Streaming; from Triple Starting from the agreement, Dubbo also supports IDL-based service definition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, Dubbo also integrates most of the industry&amp;rsquo;s mainstream protocols, allowing users to use these communication protocols within the Dubbo framework, providing users with a unified programming model and service governance model, these protocols include rest, hessian2, jsonrpc, thrift, etc. , note that there will be some differences in the range supported by different language SDK implementations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extensibility</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/extensibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/extensibility/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="extended-design-ideas">Extended Design Ideas&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Scalability is what any system pursues, and it is equally applicable to Dubbo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-scalability">What is scalability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Scalability is a design concept that represents our vision for the future. We hope that based on the existing architecture or design, when some aspects change in the future, we can adapt to this with minimal changes. kind of change.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="advantages-of-scalability">Advantages of Scalability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The advantage of scalability is mainly manifested in the decoupling between modules, which conforms to the principle of opening and closing, which is open to expansion and closed to modification. When a new function is added to the system, there is no need to modify the structure and code of the existing system, just add an extension.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ecosystem</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="dashboard">Dashboard&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/dubbo-admin">Dubbo-admin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="supported-components-and-deployment-architectures">Supported Components and Deployment Architectures&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dubbo implementations generally support the following products or deployment architectures, and specific multilingual SDK implementations may vary.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Registry
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zookeeper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nacos.io/zh-cn/docs/use-nacos-with-dubbo.html">Nacos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kubernetes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Metadata center
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zookeeper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nacos.io/zh-cn/docs/use-nacos-with-dubbo.html">Nacos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Redis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configuration center
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zookeeper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nacos.io/zh-cn/docs/use-nacos-with-dubbo.html">Nacos&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Redis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Apollo&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mesh
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data plane Envoy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Control plane Istio&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="protocols-and-interoperability">Protocols and Interoperability&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Interoperability with the gRPC system can be realized based on the Triple protocol&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Based on the REST protocol and application-level service discovery, the interoperability of the Spring Cloud system at the protocol and address discovery levels can be realized&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="spi-integration">SPI Integration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are many Dubbo extension implementations here, including protocols, serialization, registration centers, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>