<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>5 - Config Center on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/</link><description>Recent content in 5 - Config Center on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5-1 - Failed to connect to configuration center</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/1/</guid><description>Possible Reason The server where the configuration center is located is shut down or down. Wrong IP or port number. The firewall blocked the port of the configuration center by mistake. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check configuration center IP and port configuration. Check whether the server is turned on and works normally. Check whether the port used by the configuration center is allowed by the firewall or not.</description></item><item><title>5-2 - Failed to register/unregister shutdown hook method</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/2/</guid><description>Possible Reason There are exceptions in the custom hook method and business processing logic.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the custom hook method and business processing logic for runtime exceptions.</description></item><item><title>5-3 - An unexpected error occurred while destroying a method call</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/3/</guid><description>Possible Reason There is an exception in the business processing of the custom destruction method.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the custom destruction method and business processing logic for runtime exceptions.</description></item><item><title>5-4 - Method not found in service interface</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/4/</guid><description>Possible Reason The interface name#method called by the consumer does not exist. The server does not expose the current interface correctly. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the interface name# method called by the consumer exists. Check whether it exists in the service list exposed by the server.</description></item><item><title>5-5 - Unable to get env variables</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/5/</guid><description>Possible Reason Environment variable could not be obtained.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the prompted variable name, whether it is configured and can be read and loaded normally.</description></item><item><title>5-6 - Attribute Conflict of Interface Type</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/6/</guid><description>Possible Reason The generalization definition is not configured correctly.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check that the generalization definition is correct.</description></item><item><title>5-7 - An unexpected error occurred while canceling the export</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/7/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service of the configuration center cannot be connected. The configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. The client version of the configuration center conflicts with the server version, and a valid connection cannot be established. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the service status of the configuration center is normal. Check that the configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. Check whether the version of the configuration center client used is compatible with the version of the server.</description></item><item><title>5-8 - The protocol will use a random available port</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/8/</guid><description>Possible Reason The port specified by the protocol is occupied, and the port is randomly selected for startup.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the currently configured port is occupied by other applications.</description></item><item><title>5-9 - Service Configuration Export Failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/9/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service of the configuration center cannot be connected. The configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. The client version of the configuration center conflicts with the server version, and a valid connection cannot be established. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the service status of the configuration center is normal. Check that the configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. Check whether the version of the configuration center client used is compatible with the version of the server.</description></item><item><title>5-10 - Registration interface application mapping failed for service</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/10/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service metadata exposed by the service does not match the application, or has been tampered with.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check that the metadata content in the configuration center matches that in the application.</description></item><item><title>5-11 - Registration Instance Error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/11/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service of the configuration center cannot be connected. The configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. The client version of the configuration center conflicts with the server version, and a valid connection cannot be established. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the service status of the configuration center is normal. Check that the configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. Check whether the version of the configuration center client used is compatible with the version of the server.</description></item><item><title>5-12 - Refresh instance and metadata errors</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/12/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service of the configuration center cannot be connected. The configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. The client version of the configuration center conflicts with the server version, and a valid connection cannot be established. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the service status of the configuration center is normal. Check that the configured protocol, IP, and port are incorrect. Check whether the version of the configuration center client used is compatible with the version of the server.</description></item><item><title>5-13 - Model cannot be destroyed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/13/</guid><description>Possible Reason There is an exception in the business processing of the custom destruction method.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the custom destruction method and business processing logic for runtime exceptions.</description></item><item><title>5-14 - Model startup error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/14/</guid><description>Possible Reason The connection is disconnected while the service is waiting to publish or subscribe. The network connection timed out. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the connection between the application server and the configuration center is normal. Check whether there is a timeout in the network connection, etc.</description></item><item><title>5-15 - Model Reference Error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/15/</guid><description>Possible Reason The method of Dubbo core processing class is misused or tampered with.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check for misuse or decompiled modifications on the application.</description></item><item><title>5-16 - Unable to find any valid agreements</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/16/</guid><description>Possible Reason The configured protocol is not supported.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Currently supported protocols are dubbo, rmi, hessian, http, webservice, thrift, redis, etc.
see also Configuration item reference manual</description></item><item><title>5-17 - Parameter value format error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/17/</guid><description>Possible Reason The attribute configuration value is too long, generally set within 200 characters. The format of the attribute configuration value is wrong, currently supports numbers, -, _, etc. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the content of the attribute configuration value is too long, and modify it according to the prompt information. Check whether the attribute configuration value contains special characters, such as @#$%^&amp;amp;, etc. For details, please refer to the prompt information to modify.</description></item><item><title>5-18 - Notification registration event failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/18/</guid><description>Possible Reason The notification has been sent, and an unexpected error occurred in the business processing logic. The configuration center cannot be connected, timeout error. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the custom business logic implementation, whether there is a runtime exception. Check whether the configuration center can be connected normally.</description></item><item><title>5-19 - Embedded ZooKeeper running abnormally</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/19/</guid><description>Possible Reason The ZooKeeper service is running abnormally or down. The Zookeeper client version is incompatible with the server startup version and cannot be connected. The connection between the application server and the ZooKeeper service is interrupted. Restricted firewall or third-party protection tools. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the ZooKeeper service and the health status of the server where it resides. Check whether there is a compatibility problem between the Zookeeper client version and the server startup version, and keep the versions consistent.</description></item><item><title>5-20 - Error occurred while stopping dubbo module</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/20/</guid><description>Possible Reason Customize the implementation of the destruction method, and there may be exceptions when the business logic is running. The service has not been gracefully stopped, and there may be cases where the business logic has not been processed. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the custom implementation of the destruction method and business logic. Check whether there is time-consuming business processing logic when the service is stopped.</description></item><item><title>5-21 - An exception occurred when the service was destroyed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/21/</guid><description>Possible Reason The service discovery instance has been destroyed
Attachment: The current method has been discontinued in version 3.1
Troubleshooting and resolution steps</description></item><item><title>5-22 - An error occurred while initializing the registry</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/22/</guid><description>Possible Reason The address configuration of the registration center is wrong. The configured address information cannot be connected through the network normally. The version of the configuration center client does not match the version of the actual server, and there is a compatibility exception. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the configured address is correct. Check whether the network is smooth and can be connected through a third-party client. Check whether there is a compatibility matching problem, you can refer to the third-party website for version adaptation.</description></item><item><title>5-23 - Waiting for export/reference service exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/23/</guid><description>Possible Reason When exporting/referencing services, the registration center stops abnormally or fails to provide normal services externally.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the registration center can be connected normally, and check whether the current client version is compatible with the server.
Attachment: The exception is handled in the export/quote method, and theoretically this exception will not be thrown.</description></item><item><title>5-24 - An exception occurred while asynchronously waiting for the reference service</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/24/</guid><description>Possible Reason The registration center stops abnormally or cannot provide normal services to the outside world.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the registration center can be connected normally, and check whether the current client version is compatible with the server.</description></item><item><title>5-25 - Undefined exception from custom implementation</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/25/</guid><description>Possible Reason The custom implemented org.apache.dubbo.rpc.Protocol protocol has a business logic exception when the method calls destroy.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the destory method of the custom implementation class code.</description></item><item><title>5-26 - Metadata Exported</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/26/</guid><description>Possible Reason Metadata has been exported in the current JVM.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps</description></item><item><title>5-27 - Inner class API is misused</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/27/</guid><description>Possible Reason org.apache.dubbo.config.ReferenceConfig and org.apache.dubbo.common.config.ReferenceCache may be defined as non-singleton mode.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check custom annotations or configurations, define the core application class as a non-singleton mode, check scope configuration.</description></item><item><title>5-28 - No available annotation found</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/28/</guid><description>Possible Reason No reliable annotations were found under the scan package configuration. Mainly @DubboService or @Service
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the current version, @Service annotation will be scanned before 2.7.7, and @DubboService after that</description></item><item><title>5-29 - Scan package not configured</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/29/</guid><description>Possible Reason @EnableDubbo.scanBasePackages annotation parameter value is not configured
Troubleshooting and resolution steps @EnableDubbo.scanBasePackages can be configured.</description></item><item><title>5-30 - Duplicate bean definition</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/30/</guid><description>Possible Reason Duplicate object id or name declared.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps According to the fully qualified class name output by the console, the name can only be modified to be unique.</description></item><item><title>5-31 - Status Check Error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/31/</guid><description>Possible Reason Currently running server status, system CPU usage is too high or memory and other indicators are too low
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the memory usage status of the current server, and other indicators such as CPU usage, there may be a danger of downtime.</description></item><item><title>5-32 - Apollo disconnected with an error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/32/</guid><description>Possible Reason The Apollo Config Center may be down or disconnected from the network.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the service status of the Apollo server and whether the network can communicate normally.</description></item><item><title>5-33 - An exception occurred in the Apollo configuration update event</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/33/</guid><description>Possible Reason The Apollo configuration API is used incorrectly.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Please refer to the description about Apollo in the Dynamic Configuration Center Documentation.</description></item><item><title>5-34 - NACOS Error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/34/</guid><description>Possible Reason NACOS configuration API usage error.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Please refer to the description about NACOS in the Dynamic Configuration Center Documentation.</description></item><item><title>5-35 - Container initialization failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/35/</guid><description>Possible Reason The org.apache.dubbo.container.Container SPI implementation of the undefined interface.
P.S. It is currently tested and used in org.apache.dubbo.container.Main class.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps</description></item><item><title>5-36 - An error occurred during filter validation</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/36/</guid><description>Possible Reason The invoke method rewritten in the custom filter extension class has a business code exception.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>5-37 - An error occurred in the processing of dynamic configuration monitoring</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/37/</guid><description>When the file changes, the listening event processing fails
Possible Reason File permissions changed or directory permissions changed.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps The code can be located according to the stack information of the console.</description></item><item><title>5-38 - Configuration parameter undefined</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/38/</guid><description>Possible Reason configuration parameter is undefined
Troubleshooting and resolution steps It is mostly used in test cases, and parameters can be set according to the prompt details.</description></item><item><title>5-39 - An error occurred in the Dubbo configuration bean initializer</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/39/</guid><description>Possible Reason source code or modified
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check that the business code does not modify the source code or load sequence of the core class. Such as: org.apache.dubbo.config.spring.context.DubboConfigBeanInitializer</description></item><item><title>5-40 - Dubbo configuration bean not found</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/40/</guid><description>Possible Reason source code or modified
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check that the business code does not modify the source code or load sequence of the core class. Such as: org.apache.dubbo.config.spring.context.DubboConfigBeanInitializer</description></item><item><title>5-41 - Failed to read SSL certificate</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/41/</guid><description>possible reason SSL certificate configuration exception
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the configuration of the SSL certificate to see if the corresponding file exists</description></item><item><title>5-42 - Dubbo certificate issuance failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/42/</guid><description>possible reason Dubbo failed to request the remote CA to issue a certificate
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check CA connection configuration Check CA health status Check CA logs</description></item><item><title>5-43 - Dubbo certificate signing connection is not secure</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/5/43/</guid><description>possible reason Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s connection to remote CA is not secure
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the Dubbo process has correctly configured the CA certificate information and the Token acquisition method of OIDC (OpenID Connect)</description></item></channel></rss>