<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Schema Configuration Reference on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/</link><description>Recent content in Schema Configuration Reference on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>dubbo:application</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-application/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-application/</guid><description>Application configuration. The corresponding class: org.apache.dubbo.config.ApplicationConfig
Property Corresponding URL parameter Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility name application string Y service governance Application name is the unique identifier of an application. It is for registry combing the dependencies of applications. Note: Consumer and provider application name should not be the same, and this parameter is not a match condition. As a suggestion, you can name it as your project name. For example, kylin application invokes the service of morgan application, then you can name kylin application as &amp;ldquo;kylin&amp;rdquo;, and morgan application as &amp;ldquo;morgan&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:argument</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-argument/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-argument/</guid><description>Method argument configuration. The corresponding class：org.apache.dubbo.config.ArgumentConfig. This tag is child of &amp;lt;dubbo:method&amp;gt;, which is for feature description of method argument, such as:
&amp;lt;dubbo:method name=&amp;#34;findXxx&amp;#34; timeout=&amp;#34;3000&amp;#34; retries=&amp;#34;2&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dubbo:argument index=&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; callback=&amp;#34;true&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dubbo:method&amp;gt; Property Corresponding URL parameter Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility index int Y identification method name above 2.0.6 type String Index and type choose one identification Find index of argument by it above 2.0.6 callback &amp;lt;metodName&amp;gt;&amp;lt;index&amp;gt;.retries boolean N service governance Mark whether this argument is a callback service.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:config-center</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-config-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-config-center/</guid><description>Configuration center. Corresponding configuration class: org.apache.dubbo.config.ConfigCenterConfig
property Corresponding URL parameter type required default value description compatibility protocol config.protocol string optional zookeeper Which configuration center to use: apollo, zookeeper, nacos, etc.
take zookeeper for example
1. If protocol is specified, address can be simplified to 127.0.0.1:2181;
2. If protocol is not specified, address is set to zookeeper://127.0.0.1:2181 2.7.0+ address config.address string required Configuration center address.
See protocol description for values 2.7.0+ highest-priority config.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:consumer</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-consumer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-consumer/</guid><description>Consumer default configuration. The corresponding clas： org.apache.dubbo.config.ConsumerConfig. It is also default configuration of &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt;.
Property Corresponding URL parameter Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility timeout default.timeout int N 1000 performance optimization invoking timeout(ms) above 1.0.16 retries default.retries int N 2 performance optimization Invoking retry times, exclude the first invoking. Set 0 to disable it.Only valid if the cluster&amp;rsquo;s value is failback/failover above 1.0.16 loadbalance default.loadbalance string N random performance optimization Load balancing strategy.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:method</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-method/</guid><description>Method level configuration. The corresponding class: org.apache.dubbo.config.MethodConfig. This tag is a child tag of &amp;lt;dubbo:service&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt;, for accuracy to method level.
Property Corresponding URL parameter Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility name string Y identifier Method name above 1.0.8 timeout &amp;lt;metodName&amp;gt;.timeout int N &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt; timeout performance optimization Method call timeout(ms) above 1.0.8 retries &amp;lt;metodName&amp;gt;.retries int N &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt; retries performance optimization Invoking retry times, exclude the first invoking. Set 0 to disable it above 2.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:module</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-module/</guid><description>Module configuration. The corresponding class org.apache.dubbo.config.ModuleConfig
Property The corresponding class Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility name module string Y service governance Module name is for registry combing the dependencies of modules. above 2.2.0 version module.version string N service governance module version above 2.2.0 owner owner string N service governance Module manager, Pls. fill in the mailbox prefix of the person in charge above 2.2.0 organization organization string N service governance Organization name is for registry distinguishing between the source of service.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:monitor</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-monitor/</guid><description>Monitor center configuration. The corresponding class: org.apache.dubbo.config.MonitorConfig
Property The corresponding class Type Requisite Default Effect Description Compatibility protocol protocol string N dubbo service governance Monitor center protocol. &amp;ldquo;registry&amp;rdquo; means looking up monitor center from registry. Others mean communicating to monitor center directly above 2.0.9 address &amp;lt;url&amp;gt; string N N/A service governance Communicating to monitor center directly. address=&amp;ldquo;10.20.130.230:12080&amp;rdquo; above 1.0.16</description></item><item><title>dubbo:parameter</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-parameter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-parameter/</guid><description>Optional parameter configuration. The corresponding class is java.util.Map. This tag is used as a sub tag to configure custom parameters for extending &amp;lt;dubbo:protocol&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;dubbo:service&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;dubbo:provider&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;dubbo:consumer&amp;gt;.
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility key key string True Service governance routing parameter key Above 2.0.0 value value string True Service governance routing parameter value Above 2.0.0 For example：
&amp;lt;dubbo:protocol name=&amp;#34;napoli&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dubbo:parameter key=&amp;#34;http://10.20.160.198/wiki/display/dubbo/napoli.queue.name&amp;#34; value=&amp;#34;xxx&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dubbo:protocol&amp;gt; you can also use it like this:</description></item><item><title>dubbo:protocol</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-protocol/</guid><description>Service provider protocol configuration. The corresponding class is org.apache.dubbo.config.ProtocolConfig. If you need to support multiple protocols, you could declare multiple &amp;lt;dubbo:protocol&amp;gt; tags, and specify the protocol via protocol property.
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility id string False dubbo Configuration association Bean Id of the protocol, can be referenced in &amp;lt;dubbo:service protocol=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; The default value is equal to the value of name attribute while id is not filled.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:provider</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-provider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-provider/</guid><description>The default configuration of service provider. The corresponding class is org.apache.dubbo.config.ProviderConfig. This tag provider default values for &amp;lt;dubbo:service&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;dubbo:protocol&amp;gt;.
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility id string False dubbo Configuration association Bean Id of the protocol, can be referenced in &amp;lt;dubbo:service proivder=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Above 1.0.16 protocol &amp;lt;protocol&amp;gt; string False dubbo Performance optimize Protocol name Above 1.0.16 host &amp;lt;host&amp;gt; string False Find local IP automatically Service discovery The host name of services, to specify VIP and domain, or having multiple network cards.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:reference</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-reference/</guid><description>The configuration of service consumer. The corresponding class isorg.apache.dubbo.config.ReferenceConfig
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility id string True Configuration association Bean Id of the service reference Above 1.0.0 interface class True Service discovery Interface name of the service Above 1.0.0 version version string False Service discovery Service version, must be equal to the provider&amp;rsquo;s version Above 1.0.0 group group string False Service discovery The group of the service reference, must be equal to the provider&amp;rsquo;s group.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:registry</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-registry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-registry/</guid><description>The configuration of the registry center. The corresponding class is org.apache.dubbo.config.RegistryConfig. If you have multiple different registries, you can declare multiple &amp;lt;dubbo:registry&amp;gt; tags, and then reference specified registry with registry property in &amp;lt;dubbo:service&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;dubbo:reference&amp;gt; tag.
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility id string False Configuration association Bean Id of the registry center, can be referenced in &amp;lt;dubbo:service registry=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;or &amp;lt;dubbo:reference registry=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Above 1.0.16 address &amp;lt;host:port&amp;gt; string True Service discovery The address of the registry center.</description></item><item><title>dubbo:service</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/v2.7/user/references/xml/dubbo-service/</guid><description>The configuration of the service provider. The corresponding class is org.apache.dubbo.config.ServiceConfig.
Attribute Corresponding URL parameter Type Required Default Value Function Description Compatibility interface class True Service discovery The service interface name Above 1.0.0 ref object True Service discovery The reference to the service implementation Above 1.0.0 version version string False 0.0.0 Service discovery Service version. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to use 2 digitals such as 1.0. It&amp;rsquo;s necessary to upgrade version only when the service is not compatible.</description></item></channel></rss>