<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Cases on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/users/</link><description>Recent content in User Cases on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/users/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alibaba Upgrades Dubbo3 to Fully Replace HSF2</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/16/alibaba-upgrades-dubbo3-to-fully-replace-hsf2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/16/alibaba-upgrades-dubbo3-to-fully-replace-hsf2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following a comprehensive cloud migration, Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s microservice technology stack fully transitioned to a cloud-native open-source middleware system represented by Dubbo3 during the 2022 Double Eleven. In terms of business, Dubbo3 achieved a significant enhancement in user experience by maintaining continuous promotion without degradation. Technically, it greatly improved R&amp;amp;D and operational efficiency while increasing key resources&amp;rsquo; utilization rate, such as address pushing, by over 40%. The integration of Dubbo3&amp;rsquo;s open-source middleware system created Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s best practices and unified standards in the cloud, contributing scalable practical experience and technological innovation to the open-source community, becoming the core source and driving force for the development of open-source microservices technology and standards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Dubbo3 Application-Level Service Discovery Practice</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/industrial-and-commercial-bank-of-china-dubbo3-application-level-service-discovery-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/industrial-and-commercial-bank-of-china-dubbo3-application-level-service-discovery-practice/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="problem-analysis">Problem Analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The following is a classic diagram of Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s operating principle, where service providers and consumers coordinate to achieve automatic address discovery through the registration center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="icbc-analyze" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/user/icbc/icbc-analyze.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main bottleneck faced by the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China is at the registration center and service consumer end; the number of interface-level addresses has reached a scale of hundreds of millions. On one hand, storage capacity has reached its limits, and on the other hand, push efficiency has significantly declined. At the consumer end, the resident memory of the Dubbo2 framework has exceeded 40%, and each address push brings high resource consumption rates such as CPU, affecting normal business calls.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ele.me Successfully Upgrades to Dubbo3</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/ele.me-successfully-upgrades-to-dubbo3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/ele.me-successfully-upgrades-to-dubbo3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="upgrade-goals">Upgrade Goals&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="elem-arc" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/user/eleme/elem-arc.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the basic deployment architecture diagram of Ele.me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the upgrade, Ele.me&amp;rsquo;s microservice framework used HSF2, and inter-unit RPC calls were routed through a proxy. During this time, the number of machines and traffic supported by the proxy increased rapidly. Notably, after subscribing to all address data, the resource consumption and stability of the proxy faced severe challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By upgrading the entire site to Dubbo3, the business line aims to achieve two goals:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dingxiaomi Upgrades to Triple Protocol</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/dingxiaomi-upgrades-to-triple-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/dingxiaomi-upgrades-to-triple-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alibaba Cloud - DAMO Academy - Cloud Xiaomi conversational robot product is based on deep machine learning technology, natural language understanding technology, and dialogue management technology, providing enterprises with multi-engine, multi-channel, and multi-modal conversational robot services. In 2017, Cloud Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s conversational robot started public testing on the public cloud, and continuously expanded in hybrid cloud scenarios. To ensure efficiency and stability in public and hybrid cloud releases, we adopted a major version iteration every 1-2 months after much consideration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guazi Used Car Dubbo Practice</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/guazi-used-car-dubbo-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/guazi-used-car-dubbo-practice/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>  With the continuous development of Guazi&amp;rsquo;s business, the system scale is gradually expanding. Currently, there are hundreds of Dubbo applications and thousands of Dubbo instances running on Guazi’s private cloud. Various departments at Guazi are rapidly developing their businesses, and the versions have not had the chance to unify, leading to different usage styles across departments. With the construction of the second data center, the demand for a unified Dubbo version has become increasingly urgent. A production incident related to Dubbo occurred months ago, which became the catalyst for upgrading the Dubbo version in the company.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Xiaomi's Collaboration with the Dubbo Community</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/xiaomis-collaboration-with-the-dubbo-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/xiaomis-collaboration-with-the-dubbo-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>Xiaomi is devoted to making continuous contributions to the open-source community. Since the introduction of Dubbo3, internal projects are rapidly upgrading to the latest version of Dubbo. Currently, the number of instances has been upgraded to a certain proportion. Not only have performance improvements been seen, but services are also running smoothly with improvements in availability. Statistics provide proof that Dubbo’s switch from API-level discovery to application-level discovery has improved the availability and reliability of service discovery, leading to lower operation costs. In addition, using ProtoBuf for serialization and deserialization has reduced the data exchange size. Lastly, full compatibility with gRPC provides convenience to Xiaomi’s multi-language development environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zhonglun Network Dubbo3 Upgrade Practice</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/zhonglun-network-dubbo3-upgrade-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/zhonglun-network-dubbo3-upgrade-practice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Zhonglun Network completed a full upgrade from Dubbo2 to Dubbo3 in 2022, deeply utilizing core capabilities such as application-level service discovery, Kubernetes native service deployment, and service governance. The technical leader from Zhonglun Network, Lai Binbin, provided an in-depth summary of the selection, upgrade process, and benefits of Dubbo3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that the recent &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/">Dubbo3 official documentation&lt;/a> has undergone significant enhancements, and the community has committed substantial effort to improving the documentation in the near term, which is crucial for the use of Dubbo3 and the enhancement of user confidence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Migration Journey of Ping An Health to Dubbo3</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/the-migration-journey-of-ping-an-health-to-dubbo3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/the-migration-journey-of-ping-an-health-to-dubbo3/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="1-background">1 Background&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Our company has used Dubbo as a microservice framework since 2015. When the community launched Dubbo3, we immediately followed suit and conducted in-depth research. We found that the application/instance-level service registration and discovery model of Dubbo3 could alleviate some pressure faced by our current registration center, addressing stability and security issues. At the same time, Dubbo3 has upgraded service governance, aligning with cloud-native architecture, and is backward compatible with Dubbo2, which lowers the cost and risk of upgrading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First National Government-Enterprise Procurement Cloud Platform: The Mixed Cloud Cross-Network Solution Practice of Zhengcai Cloud</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/03/22/the-first-national-government-enterprise-procurement-cloud-platform-the-mixed-cloud-cross-network-solution-practice-of-zhengcai-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/03/22/the-first-national-government-enterprise-procurement-cloud-platform-the-mixed-cloud-cross-network-solution-practice-of-zhengcai-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>For companies with a cloud-island business structure, the cloud platform is an internal, fully controllable local area network, while the island end is an independent internal network with its own security network policy. When cloud-island communication is required, certain ports need to be opened based on demand and customer requirements, which incurs costs and is not completely controllable. If the demand for cross-network communication increases, it will gradually become a pain point. If a transparent cross-network transmission network can be established, along with good top-level design, a better balance can be sought in business support, security control, and operational costs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>