<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>6 - Transport on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/</link><description>Recent content in 6 - Transport on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>6-1 - Server Connection Failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/1/</guid><description>Network communication layer, failed to connect to the service provider service
Possible Reason The service provider&amp;rsquo;s network is abnormally disconnected or blocked by firewalls and third-party tools, and cannot provide external services.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps If it is a rest connection, check whether the requested server configuration is correct. Check whether the network communication is normal, you can use some simple cmd commands to detect, such as ping and so on.</description></item><item><title>6-2 - Client Timeout</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/2/</guid><description>Timeout occurs when the caller fails to obtain the corresponding response within the specified time after the request is sent.
Possible Reason The server is really slow in processing and cannot return the result within the specified time. The caller will automatically return a timeout exception response to end the call. If the server responds quickly, but when the client load is high and the load pressure is high, it will time out due to problems such as the client request not being sent out or the response stuck in the TCP Buffer.</description></item><item><title>6-3 - Failed to close network connection</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/3/</guid><description>Network connection close failed
Possible Reason Non-graceful shutdown of the service. At this time, the server may not complete the external output stream.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Generally, it is a prompt warning message, which does not affect subsequent program execution.</description></item><item><title>6-4 - Network communication layer unknown exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/4/</guid><description>Reminder The meaning of this error code has been adjusted. If you are looking for information of this error code in Dubbo versions prior than (or equal) 3.1.4 or 3.2.0-beta.3, head to 99-0.
(This error code is currently absent.)</description></item><item><title>6-5 - Network disconnection failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/5/</guid><description>Timeout occurs when the caller fails to obtain the corresponding response within the specified time after the request is sent.
Possible Reason Client actively disconnects
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Generally, it is a prompt warning message, which does not affect subsequent program execution.</description></item><item><title>6-6 - Unsupported message</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/6/</guid><description>Possible Reason The returned data is serialized incorrectly, or exceeds the serialization maximum
Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.
For the specific configuration items and meanings supported by each component, please refer to Configuration Item Manual</description></item><item><title>6-7 - Thread Connection Exceeded Warning</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/7/</guid><description>Reminder message when the number of connections exceeds the limit
Possible Reason A warning reminder that the configuration or the number of connections exceeds the configured number.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps The default configuration item connect.queue.warning.size=1000 can be adjusted through configuration.</description></item><item><title>6-8 - Return data decoding failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/8/</guid><description>Possible Reason Return data format error or decoding failed
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Through the debug/warn log mode, the specific service class name and the returned message and stack information can be output.</description></item><item><title>6-9 - There are duplicate serial number IDs</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/9/</guid><description>Possible Reason An empty object is returned. The custom serial number class, org.apache.dubbo.common.serialize.Serialization#getContentTypeId is duplicated with the built-in system, At this time, when loading, the first loaded SPI instance shall prevail. Other items will be skipped. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the return result. The built-in value can refer to the class org.apache.dubbo.common.serialize.Constants</description></item><item><title>6-10 - Payload Limit Exceeded Exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/10/</guid><description>The default payload=8M, please check the configuration
Possible Reason Troubleshooting and resolution steps For the specific configuration items and meanings supported by each component, please refer to Configuration Item Manual</description></item><item><title>6-11 - Character set not supported</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/11/</guid><description>Default UTF-8 charset
Possible Reason Troubleshooting and resolution steps The result will end up being processed in the UTF-8 character set.</description></item><item><title>6-12 - An error occurred when the ZK client was destroyed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/12/</guid><description>Possible Reason The connection between the client and the server has been refused When the client is being destroyed, the server may be performing elections or other operations, resulting in an exception.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps The shutdown method can be used to query stack information. Generally do not deal with.</description></item><item><title>6-13 - Stream closed exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/13/</guid><description>Possible Reason Stream is closed or the stream is closed while other threads are reading
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Generally, the order in which the code closes the streams is reversed.</description></item><item><title>6-14 - Server response failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/14/</guid><description>Possible Reason When the server interacts with the client to generate data, the client closes abnormally.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps The client terminated abnormally or the server crashed.</description></item><item><title>6-15 - Skip unread stream data</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/15/</guid><description>When decoding, if there is unread data in the stream, the unread stream will be skipped
Possible Reason Troubleshooting and resolution steps When decoding, all the data will be read at one time</description></item><item><title>6-16 - An exception occurred during reconnection</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/6/16/</guid><description>Prompt every time a reconnection occurs
Possible Reason Delayed reconnection caused by network instability.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check for network packet loss.</description></item></channel></rss>