<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles About Apache Dubbo on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/news/</link><description>Recent content in Articles About Apache Dubbo on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracing Dubbo With OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/01/31/tracing-dubbo-with-opentelemetry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/01/31/tracing-dubbo-with-opentelemetry/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This case shows using OpenTelemetry(otlp) as the Tracer in the Dubbo project to report the Trace information to the Otlp Collector, which then forwards it to Zipkin and Jagger. &lt;a href="https://github.com/conghuhu/dubbo-samples/tree/master/4-governance/dubbo-samples-tracing/dubbo-samples-spring-boot-tracing-otel-otlp">Code address&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It consists of three parts：&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>dubbo-samples-spring-boot-tracing-otel-oltp-interface&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dubbo-samples-spring-boot-tracing-otel-oltp-provider&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dubbo-samples-spring-boot-tracing-otel-oltp-consumer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="architecture architecture" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/v3/tasks/observability/tracing/otlp/demo_arch.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quick-start">Quick Start&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="install--start-otlp-collector">Install &amp;amp; start Otlp Collector&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Follow &lt;a href="https://OpenTelemetry.io/docs/collector/getting-started/">OpenTelemetry Collector Quick Start&lt;/a> to start the otlp collector.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="start-provider">Start Provider&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Run &lt;code>org.apache.dubbo.springboot.demo.provider.ProviderApplication&lt;/code> directly from IDE.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="start-consumer">Start Consumer&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Start &lt;code>org.apache.dubbo.springboot.demo.consumer.ConsumerApplication&lt;/code> directly from IDE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to Apache Dubbo plugin for IntelliJ IDEA</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/23/introduction-to-apache-dubbo-plugin-for-intellij-idea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/23/introduction-to-apache-dubbo-plugin-for-intellij-idea/</guid><description>&lt;p>The most popular Java IDE, IntelliJ IDEA, has collaborated with the open-source microservice framework Apache Dubbo community, bringing good news to microservice developers. Along with IntelliJ IDEA version 2023.2, Jetbras has officially released the new &lt;strong>Apache Dubbo in Spring Framework&lt;/strong> plugin version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This plugin can help developers with Dubbo project initialization and facilitate the identification of Dubbo services and their dependencies during the project development process. Developing microservices based on Apache Dubbo will become very simple.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced cloud native - Dubbo 3.2 officially released</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/04/15/advanced-cloud-native-dubbo-3.2-officially-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/04/15/advanced-cloud-native-dubbo-3.2-officially-released/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background-introduction">Background introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an RPC service development framework, which is used to solve service governance and communication problems under the microservice architecture. It officially provides multi-language SDK implementations such as Java and Golang. The microservices developed using Dubbo are natively capable of remote address discovery and communication with each other. Using the rich service governance features provided by Dubbo, service governance demands such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic scheduling can be realized. Dubbo is designed to be highly scalable, and users can easily implement various custom logics for traffic interception and location selection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to proxy Dubbo service in Apache ShenYu Gateway</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/05/04/how-to-proxy-dubbo-service-in-apache-shenyu-gateway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/05/04/how-to-proxy-dubbo-service-in-apache-shenyu-gateway/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/shenyu-dubbo/ApacheShenYu-Dubbo-en.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Apache ShenYu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/shenyu-dubbo/shenyu.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shenyu.apache.org/docs/index">Apache ShenYu(Incubating)&lt;/a> is an asynchronous, high-performance, cross-language, responsive &lt;code>API&lt;/code> gateway. Compatible with a variety of mainstream framework systems, support for hot-plugging, users can customize the development to meet the current and future needs of users in a variety of scenarios, experienced large-scale scenarios hammered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May 2021, &lt;code>ShenYu&lt;/code> was donated to the &lt;code>Apache&lt;/code> Software Foundation, and the Apache Foundation voted unanimously to enter the incubator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Makes it More Convenient for You to Proxy Dubbo Services in Apache APISIX</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/01/18/makes-it-more-convenient-for-you-to-proxy-dubbo-services-in-apache-apisix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/01/18/makes-it-more-convenient-for-you-to-proxy-dubbo-services-in-apache-apisix/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/">Apache Dubbo&lt;/a> is a MicroService development framework open sourced by Alibaba and donated to Apache, which provides two key capabilities of RPC communication and microservice governance. It has not only been validated by Ali&amp;rsquo;s massive traffic in e-commerce scenario, but also been widely implemented in domestic technology companies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In practical application scenarios, Apache Dubbo is generally used as the implementation framework for RPC calls between back-end systems, and when HTTP interfaces need to be provided to the front-end, the Dubbo Service is packaged as an HTTP interface through a &amp;ldquo;glue layer&amp;rdquo; and then delivered to the front-end system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Admin service test</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/08/26/service-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/08/26/service-test/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based on the metadata of Dubbo2.7, Dubbo Admin implements the service test function, which can call the real service provider on the console through generalized call.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="usage">Usage&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Deploy the provider: You can download the demo &lt;a href="https://github.com/nzomkxia/dubbo-demo">here&lt;/a>. This project is based on Spring Boot, which is convenient to start in the IDE or command line. For service testing, you only need to start &lt;code>dubbo-basic-provider&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Service-seeking: After completing the server deployment, you can query the corresponding service on the Dubbo Admin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>service test&lt;/code> page:
&lt;img alt="testSearch" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/admin/testSearch.jpg">&lt;br>
the information here is similar to the metadata, including the method name, parameter type and return value. Click the label on the right to enter the &lt;code>service test&lt;/code> page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tracing Dubbo service with Apache Skywalking</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/08/11/tracing-dubbo-service-with-apache-skywalking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/08/11/tracing-dubbo-service-with-apache-skywalking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-apache-skywalking">Introduction to Apache Skywalking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/skywalking">Apache Skywalking&lt;/a> is the APM system that it designed for micro-services architectures and cloud native architecture systems and supports distribute tracking. &lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/skywalking">Apache skywalking (incubator)&lt;/a> collects and analyzes the trace data and generates the relationship between the application and the service metric, Apache skywalking supports multiple languages agent, for example &lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/skywalking">Java&lt;/a>,&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenSkywalking/skywalking-netcore">.net core&lt;/a>,&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenSkywalking/skywalking-nodejs">Node.js&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/SkyAPM/go2sky">Go&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, Skywalking has supported analysis the operation of distributed systems from 6 visual dimensions. The overview view is a global view of your applications and components, including the number of components and applications, application alarm fluctuations, slow service lists, and application throughput; The topology shows the topological relationship of the whole application; The application view represents the upstream and downstream relationship of the application from single application, TOP N services and servers, JVM, host and process info. The service view focuses on the operation of a single service portal and the upstream and downstream dependencies of this service and it helps the user to optimize and monitor a single service; the trace graph shows all the buried points of the invocation and the execution time of each burial point, and the alarm view is based on the configuration threshold for the application, server, service for real-time alarms&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo extensible mechanism source code analysis - part 2</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/05/02/dubbo-extensible-mechanism-source-code-analysis-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/05/02/dubbo-extensible-mechanism-source-code-analysis-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/04/25/dubbo-extensible-mechanism-source-code-analysis-part-1/">actual implementation of the Dubbo extensibility mechanism&lt;/a>, we learned some concepts of the Dubbo extension mechanism, explored the implementation of LoadBalance in Dubbo, and implemented a LoadBalance on our own. Do you think Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s extension mechanism is great? Next, we will go deep into the source code of Dubbo and see what it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="extensionloader">ExtensionLoader&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;code>ExtensionLoader&lt;/code> is the core class, which is responsible for the loading and lifecycle management of extension points. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with this class. There are many methods of Extension, and the common methods include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo extensible mechanism source code analysis - part 1</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/04/25/dubbo-extensible-mechanism-source-code-analysis-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/04/25/dubbo-extensible-mechanism-source-code-analysis-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-extension-mechanism-of-dubbo">1. Extension Mechanism of Dubbo&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dubbo is claimed as a high-performance RPC framework on its official website. Today, I want to talk about another great specialty of Dubbo &amp;mdash; its scalability. As quote: Rome wasn’t built in a day. Any successful system always starts as a prototype. It is impossible to design a perfect system at the beginning. Instead, we should focus on true demand and keep improving the system. On the coding side, it requires us to pay attention on abstraction layers and high-level isolation. In that case, the system could keep a healthy structure and easy to maintain while new features or third-party extensions are added. Under some circumstances, a designer should pursue more of scalability than the system’s current performance.
When talking about software design, people always mention scalability. A framework with good scalability requires the following:
1.The framework should follow opening/closed principle: software entities should be open for extension, but closed for modification; This means a framework should allow the maintainer to add new functions with as few modifications as possible.
2.The framework should allow the user to add new functions by adding code on his project without modifying the framework&amp;rsquo;s original source code base.
With microkernel architecture and extension mechanism, Dubbo satisfies such requirements and achieves good scalability. In the following chapters, we will discuss Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s extension mechanism in detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementation background and practice of Dubbo client asynchronous interface</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/02/20/implementation-background-and-practice-of-dubbo-client-asynchronous-interface/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/02/20/implementation-background-and-practice-of-dubbo-client-asynchronous-interface/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="image | left" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/dubboasyn_client/1_en.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a brief introduction about the stages of a complete Dubbo invocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Biz~ represents business thread, that is, the thread where the business logic is located. Biz~ thread pool may be created and maintained by business itself, most of which may be managed by system framework itself (for example, a web system runs under Tomcat container, Biz~ thread is maintained by Tomcat); IO~ stands for network data processing thread, which is created and maintained by IO framework (such as Netty, Grizzly). Dubbo Remoting&amp;rsquo;s default Netty implementation is NioEventloopLoopGroup. In addition, according to the binding relationship between Channel and IO thread, IO~ can also be regarded as an acceptable Channel for event messages. Asynchronous processing stages such as Biz and IO are abstractly described in JDK8 as completionstages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementation background and practice of Dubbo server asynchronous interface</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/02/20/implementation-background-and-practice-of-dubbo-server-asynchronous-interface/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/02/20/implementation-background-and-practice-of-dubbo-server-asynchronous-interface/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is suggested to make an understanding of the thread phase involved in the process of Dubbo first, please refer to &lt;a href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/02/20/implementation-background-and-practice-of-dubbo-client-asynchronous-interface/">Implementation background and practice of Dubbo client asynchronous interface&lt;/a> for details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="implementation-background">Implementation background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is necessary to introduce the server-side thread strategy in more detail to deepen the user&amp;rsquo;s judgment basis for selecting server-side asynchrony. It is also necessary to introduce coroutines, the &amp;ldquo;secret weapon&amp;rdquo; often used in server-side asynchrony.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to use Seata to ensure consistency between Dubbo Microservices</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/01/17/how-to-use-seata-to-ensure-consistency-between-dubbo-microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/01/17/how-to-use-seata-to-ensure-consistency-between-dubbo-microservices/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A business logic for user purchasing commodities. The whole business logic is powered by 3 microservices:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Storage service: deduct storage count on given commodity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Order service: create order according to purchase request.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Account service: debit the balance of user&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Architecture" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/fescar/fescar-1.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="storageservice">StorageService&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">interface&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">StorageService&lt;/span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#586e75">/**
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> * deduct storage count
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> */&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">void&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">deduct&lt;/span>(String commodityCode, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> count);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="orderservice">OrderService&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">interface&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">OrderService&lt;/span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#586e75">/**
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> * create order
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> */&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Order &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">create&lt;/span>(String userId, String commodityCode, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> orderCount);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="accountservice">AccountService&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">interface&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">AccountService&lt;/span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#586e75">/**
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> * debit balance of user&amp;#39;s account
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> */&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">void&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">debit&lt;/span>(String userId, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> money);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="main-business-logic">Main business logic&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">BusinessServiceImpl&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">implements&lt;/span> BusinessService {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">private&lt;/span> StorageService storageService;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">private&lt;/span> OrderService orderService;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#586e75">/**
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> * purchase
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#586e75"> */&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">void&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">purchase&lt;/span>(String userId, String commodityCode, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> orderCount) {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> storageService.deduct(commodityCode, orderCount);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> orderService.create(userId, commodityCode, orderCount);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">StorageServiceImpl&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">implements&lt;/span> StorageService {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">private&lt;/span> StorageDAO storageDAO;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> 
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">@Override&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">void&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">deduct&lt;/span>(String commodityCode, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> count) {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Storage storage &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#719e07">new&lt;/span> Storage();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> storage.setCount(count);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> storage.setCommodityCode(commodityCode);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> storageDAO.update(storage);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">OrderServiceImpl&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">implements&lt;/span> OrderService {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">private&lt;/span> OrderDAO orderDAO;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">private&lt;/span> AccountService accountService;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">public&lt;/span> Order &lt;span style="color:#268bd2">create&lt;/span>(String userId, String commodityCode, &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> orderCount) {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#dc322f">int&lt;/span> orderMoney &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> calculate(commodityCode, orderCount);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> accountService.debit(userId, orderMoney);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Order order &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#719e07">new&lt;/span> Order();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> order.userId &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> userId;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> order.commodityCode &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> commodityCode;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> order.count &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> orderCount;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> order.money &lt;span style="color:#719e07">=&lt;/span> orderMoney;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#719e07">return&lt;/span> orderDAO.insert(order);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="distributed-transaction-solution-with-seata">Distributed Transaction Solution with Seata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="undefined" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/fescar/fescar-2.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The fifth Dubbo meetup has been held in Hangzhou</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/12/10/the-fifth-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-hangzhou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/12/10/the-fifth-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-hangzhou/</guid><description>&lt;p>The fifth Dubbo meetup has been held in Hangzhou,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please enjoy the slides of the topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ding Li: How to involve in dubbo community &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/how-to-involve-in-dubbo-community.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shenli Cao: Dubbo 2.7 introduction &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/dubbo-2.7-introduction.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tao Yang: Dubbo practice in netease koala &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/dubbo-practice-in-netease-koala.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mercy Ma: Nacos support in Dubbo &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/nacos-support-in-dubbo.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yihao Zhao: Sentinel: Sentinel support for Dubbo &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/sentinel-support-for-dubbo.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zhixuan Chen: Troubleshooting Dubbo with Arthas &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/troubleshooting-dubbo-with-arthas.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Integrates with Nacos to Become a Registry</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/11/07/dubbo-integrates-with-nacos-to-become-a-registry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/11/07/dubbo-integrates-with-nacos-to-become-a-registry/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nacos is an important registry in Dubbo ecosystem, and dubbo-registry-nacos is the implementation of Dubbo-integrated Nacos registry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="preparation-works">Preparation Works&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you integrate dubbo-registry-nacos into your Dubbo project, make sure the Nacos service is started in the background. If you are not familiar with the basic use of Nacos, you can refer to the Quick Start for Nacos: &lt;a href="https://nacos.io/en-us/docs/quick-start.html">https://nacos.io/en-us/docs/quick-start.html&lt;/a>. Nacos versions above 0.6.1 are recommended.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-started-quickly">Get Started Quickly&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The operation steps for Dubbo to integrate Nacos into a registry are simple, the general steps can be divided into &amp;ldquo;add Maven dependency&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;configure the registry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Dubbo protocol</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/10/05/introduction-to-the-dubbo-protocol/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/10/05/introduction-to-the-dubbo-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-concept-of-the-protocol">The concept of the protocol&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The protocol is the foundation of communication between two network entities, and data is transmitted from one entity to another in the form of a byte stream over the network. In the world of byte streams, this one-dimensional byte stream cannot be reshaped into two-dimensional or multi-dimensional data structures and domain objects without a protocol.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-the-protocol">What is the protocol&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The protocol is the semantics determined by both parties for the communication. For example, we design a protocol for string transmission, which allows the client to send a string and the server receives the corresponding string.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrate Dubbo with Kubernetes</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/30/integrate-dubbo-with-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/30/integrate-dubbo-with-kubernetes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="general-goal">General goal&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s provider don&amp;rsquo;t care about service registration.Open its Dubbo service port,the declaration and publishment of the service will be executed by Kubernetes.
Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s consumer directly discovers the corresponding service endpoints of Kubernetes during service discovery procedure, thereby reusing Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s existing microservice channel capabilities.The benefit is that there is no need to rely on any third-party soft-loaded registry and it can be seamlessly integrated into the multi-tenant security system of Kubernetes. Reference demo : &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/dubbo-Kubernetes">https://github.com/dubbo/dubbo-ubernetes&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to prepare an Apache Release</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-prepare-an-apache-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-prepare-an-apache-release/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-apache-release-cycle">Understanding the Apache Release Cycle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In general, Source Release is the key and the required content of Apache. But Binary Release is optional, Dubbo can choose whether to release binary packages to the Apache repository or to the Maven central repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please refer to the following links for more information on ASF&amp;rsquo;s release guide:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/release-publishing">Apache Release Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/release.html">Apache Release Policy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/publishing-maven-artifacts.html">Maven Release Info&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="preparation-of-local-building-environment">Preparation of Local Building Environment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mainly including the related preparation of signature utilities and Maven repository certification&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to implement a fully asynchronous calls chain based on Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-implement-a-fully-asynchronous-calls-chain-based-on-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-implement-a-fully-asynchronous-calls-chain-based-on-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Implementing the full asynchronous programming based on Dubbo, which is a new feature introduced in version 2.7.0 after the enhancement of the existing asynchronous mode.This article first reviews the supported functions and existing problems of asynchronization in 2.6.x and earlier versions, and introduces the targeted enhancements based on CompletableFuture in version 2.7.0. Then, the use of enhanced asynchronous programming is elaborated through several examples. Finally, it summarizes the new problems brought by the introduction of asynchronous mode and corresponding solutions from Dubbo. By reading this article, it is easy to implement a fully asynchronous remote service call chain based on Dubbo 2.7.0+.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The fourth Dubbo meetup has been held in Chengdu</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/26/the-fourth-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-chengdu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/26/the-fourth-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-chengdu/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-fourth-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-chengdu">The fourth Dubbo meetup has been held in Chengdu&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/meetup-chengdu/all-hands.webp">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-depth-of-the-user-communication">The depth of the user communication&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On August 26, 10:00 am - 12:00am, invited the arrival of the car to help, cloud gold, former BBD, flying fish star four companies open source enthusiasts and heavy users participate in face-to-face communication;According to the participants&amp;rsquo; feedback, answer to Dubbo many doubt, especially how to participate in the contribution to the community, as well as code contribution value point.Hope later can be more deeply involved in Dubbo communities and activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Dubbo Basic Usage - Dubbo Consumer Configuration</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-basic-usage-dubbo-consumer-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-basic-usage-dubbo-consumer-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dubbo-consumer-configuration">Dubbo Consumer Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="consumer-configuration-detailed">Consumer Configuration Detailed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are 3 ways to configure the Dubbo Consumer: XML configuration, API call mode configuration, and annotation mode configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="xml-configuration">XML Configuration&lt;/h4>
&lt;h6 id="example-of-the-simplest-configuration">Example of the simplest configuration:&lt;/h6>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;beans xmlns=&amp;#34;http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Xmlns:xsi=&amp;#34;http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Xmlns:dubbo=&amp;#34;http://dubbo.apache.org/schema/dubbo&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Xsi:schemaLocation=&amp;#34;http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans/spring-beans-4.3.xsd http://dubbo.apache.org/schema /dubbo http://dubbo.apache.org/schema/dubbo/dubbo.xsd&amp;#34;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &amp;lt;dubbo:application name=&amp;#34;hello-world-app&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &amp;lt;dubbo:registry address=&amp;#34;multicast://224.5.6.7:1234&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &amp;lt;dubbo:protocol name=&amp;#34;dubbo&amp;#34; port=&amp;#34;20880&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &amp;lt;dubbo:reference id=&amp;#34;demoServiceRemote&amp;#34; interface=&amp;#34;com.alibaba.dubbo.demo.DemoService&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;/beans&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For the supported configuration tags and corresponding configuration items, refer to the usage in the provider.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo: Several ways about synchronous/asynchronous invoke</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-several-ways-about-synchronous/asynchronous-invoke/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-several-ways-about-synchronous/asynchronous-invoke/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we all know，Dubbo adopts a single large join protocol by default and takes the NIO asynchronous communication mechanism of Netty as the low-level implementation. Based on this mechanism, Dubbo implements several invocation modes as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>synchronous invoke&lt;/li>
&lt;li>asynchronous invoke&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parameters callback&lt;/li>
&lt;li>event notification&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="synchronous-invoke">Synchronous invoke&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Synchronous invoke is a kind of blocking invocation mode, that is the Consumer keeps blocking and waiting, until the Provider returns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally, a typical synchronous invocation process is as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Basic Usage -- Dubbo Provider Configuration</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-basic-usage--dubbo-provider-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/dubbo-basic-usage--dubbo-provider-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;p>This chapter mainly talking about how to configure dubbo. According to the configuration mode, it can be divided into the following mode: XML Configuration, Properties Configuration, Annotation Configuration, API Invocation Mode Configuration. And according to the function, we can divide them into Dubbo Provider and Dubbo Consumer. In the following sections, we would explain Dubbo Provider and Dubbo Consumer respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dubbo-provider-configuration">Dubbo Provider Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="provider-configuration-in-detail">Provider Configuration in Detail&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The configuration mode of Dubbo Provider has 4 different ways: XML Configuration, Properties Configuration, API Invocation Mode Configuration and Annotation Configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manipulating Services Dynamically via QoS</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/manipulating-services-dynamically-via-qos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/manipulating-services-dynamically-via-qos/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="manipulating-services-dynamically-via-qos">Manipulating Services Dynamically via QoS&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>QoS (short form of &lt;strong>Quality of Service&lt;/strong>), is a common terminology talking about network devices. For example, by adjusting and manipulating the weights of ports of a router dynamically via QoS, engineers could give priority to services running on these ports and make sure these services&amp;rsquo; quality and reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Dubbo, QoS is used to query and manipulate services dynamically, like getting a list of active provider and consumer services, and launching or withdrawing services (i.e registering to or unregistering services from registration center).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Source code analysis of spring-boot+Dubbo App start and stop</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/source-code-analysis-of-spring-boot-dubbo-app-start-and-stop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/source-code-analysis-of-spring-boot-dubbo-app-start-and-stop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/dubbo-spring-boot-project">Dubbo Spring Boot&lt;/a> project is dedicated to simplifying the development of the Dubbo RPC framework in the Spring Boot application. It also integrates the feature of Spring Boot:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/dubbo-spring-boot-project/blob/master/dubbo-spring-boot-autoconfigure">Autoconfigure&lt;/a> (ex: Annotation driver, Autoconfigure, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/dubbo-spring-boot-project/blob/master/dubbo-spring-boot-actuator">Production-Ready&lt;/a> (ex: Security, Healthy check, Externalize configuration, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="the-analysis-of-dubboconsumer-startup">The analysis of DubboConsumer startup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have you ever thought about this : since the &lt;code>DubboConsumerDemo&lt;/code> application in &lt;code>dubbo-spring-boot-project&lt;/code> has only one line of code, why not just exit directly when the &lt;code>main&lt;/code> method is executed?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementation of cross-language calls by Dubbo2.js</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/implementation-of-cross-language-calls-by-dubbo2.js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/implementation-of-cross-language-calls-by-dubbo2.js/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/dubbo2.js">dubbo2.js&lt;/a> is a Dubbo client for node.js developped by &lt;a href="https://www.qianmi.com/">Qianmiwang&lt;/a>. It supports Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s native protocol, which makes the RPC calls between javascript and java efficient and agile. This tool has been contributed to Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s community.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="cross-language-calls-for-micro-service">Cross-language calls for micro service&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nowadays, Internet architecture tends to be micro-service way. The discussions about micro-service architecture becomes the most mentioned topic in different technical conferences. In China, most of the companies, such as Qianmiwang, choose Dubbo as their micro-servie architecture solution. As most of the internet companies, Qianmiwang uses various of programming languages. Java is for most of the backend services. Each business based on these backend can choose its own programming language such as go, python and javascript. Therefore, here comes a challenge, cross language calls. Some well mentioned solutions are as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generic invoke of Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/generic-invoke-of-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/generic-invoke-of-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="generic-invoke-of-dubbo">Generic invoke of Dubbo&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The generic invoke could be considered to be used in the following cases:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Service test platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API service gateway&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The generic invoke is mainly used when the consumer does not have an API interface;
instead of depending the interface jar package, the service call is initiated directly through the GenericService interface, and all POJOs in the parameters and return values are represented by a &lt;code>Map&lt;/code>.
Generic invoke does not require attention on the server and can be exposed as normal services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Native Image using GraalVM</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/native-image-using-graalvm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/native-image-using-graalvm/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This document will show you how to access GraalVM with a dubbo project and how to compile the project to a binary executable using native-image. The document also introduces the efforts we made in achieving this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GraalVM&amp;rsquo;s essential is the Graal compiler, an excellent just-in-time (JIT) compiler. It can be used as both a JIT compiler and a static compiler for ahead-of-time compilation. Graal compiler completes the primary compilation work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo's Load Balance</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/10/dubbos-load-balance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/10/dubbos-load-balance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dubbo is a distributed service framework that avoids single point of failure and horizontal expansion of support services. A service typically deploys multiple instances. How to select a call from a cluster of multiple service providers involves a load balancing strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="concepts">Concepts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before discussing load balancing, I will explain these three concepts first.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Load Balancing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fault-tolerant Cluster&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service Route&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>These three concepts are confusing. They all describe how to choose from multiple Providers to make calls. So what is the difference between them? Let me give a simple example and explain these concepts clearly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Annotations In Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/use-annotations-in-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/use-annotations-in-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the widely promotion and implementation of Microservices Architecture, the Microservices Architecture represented by Spring Boot and Spring Cloud, in Java ecosystem, introduced some brand new programming model, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Annotation-Driven&lt;/li>
&lt;li>External Configuration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-Configure&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>New programming model have some advantages, for example, it does not require &lt;code>XML&lt;/code> configuration, it can simplify deployment process, beyond that，it can promote development efficiency. In order to implement the microservice architecture better，Dubbo has provided more perfect support for the above three scenarios since version 2.5.8. This article focuses on introduce annotations rather than discuss the traditional XML configuration approach. There are two kinds of automatic assembly, external configuration and automatic assembly, will be introduced in another aricle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Zookeeper in Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/using-zookeeper-in-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/using-zookeeper-in-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-of-zookeeper">Introduction of Zookeeper&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-basic-concept">The basic concept&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the mordern distrbuted applications, there are multiple coordination problems between nodes and nodes, including: leader election, group service, locking, configuration management, naming and synchronization. Apache Zookeeper, as its name implied, is a distributed, open-source coordination service framwork to address these demand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to ensure the high performance, highly available and strictly ordered access, the performance aspects of ZooKeeper means it can be used in large, distributed systems and can also be deployed in cluster mode, which called &amp;lsquo;ZooKeeper ensemble&amp;rsquo;. In ZooKeeper ensemble, all write requests from clients are forwarded to a single server, called the leader, through the ZAB(Zookeeper Atomic Broadcast Protocol) to make sure the message in each nodes are same. Clients can access any one of the clusters to read and write data without worrying about inconsistencies in the data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your First Dubbo Demo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/dubbo-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/07/dubbo-101/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="java-rmi-introduction">Java RMI Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Java RMI (Remote Method Invocation) is a mechanism that allows users to access or invocate an object and a method running on another JVM (Java Virtual Machine). RMI is an implementation of RPC (Remote Procedure Call) in java with support of OOP (Object Oriented Paradigms). Instead of bothering IDL (Interface Define Language), users can build distributed applications by depending on interfaces in an easy and natural way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The third Dubbo meetup has been held in Shenzhen</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/30/the-third-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-shenzhen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/30/the-third-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-shenzhen/</guid><description>&lt;p>The third Dubbo meetup has successfully been held in Shenzhen, over 2000 people submitted registration, and over 700 were present, more than 17,000 watched the live online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please enjoy the slides of the topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zhixuan Chen: Dubbo-present-and-2.7-update (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201807%40shenzhen/dubbo-present-and-2.7-update.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bin Kang: Microservice-in-lexinfintech (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201807%40shenzhen/microservice-in-lexinfintech.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jialiang lin: sentinel (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201807%40shenzhen/sentinel.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Sentinel: The flow sentinel of Dubbo services</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/27/sentinel-the-flow-sentinel-of-dubbo-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/27/sentinel-the-flow-sentinel-of-dubbo-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>In large clusters there may be thousands of Dubbo service instances in production, with continuous traffic coming in. However, in distributed systems, some services may be unavailable due to various of failure such as traffic surge, high system load, and network latency. If no control actions are performed, this may cause cascading failure, affecting the availability of the service. So we need a powerful library - Sentinel, which can guarantee the stability of the service, to protect the Dubbo service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tracking with Pinpoint</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/12/tracking-with-pinpoint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/12/tracking-with-pinpoint/</guid><description>&lt;p>After using Dubbo to serve or integrate applications, assuming that a service backstage log shows an exception and that the service is invoked by multiple applications, it is often difficult to determine which application is called, and what is the cause of the problem, so we need a set of distributed tracking systems to quickly locate the problem. Pinpoint can help us quickly locate problems (of course, there are more than one solution).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your First Dubbo Filter</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/01/your-first-dubbo-filter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/01/your-first-dubbo-filter/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In overall design of Dubbo, Filter is a very important concept, most of Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s functions are based on this
extension point, and the Filter interception will be executed during each call.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="extension-mechanism-of-dubbo-filter">Extension Mechanism of Dubbo Filter&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There are already about 20 Filters implemented in Dubbo. Their entry is ProtocolFilterWrapper, ProtocolFilterWrapper
makes a Wrapper on Protocol and will be loaded when the extension is loaded. Then, let&amp;rsquo;s see how
the Filter chain is constructed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The second Dubbo Shanghai meetup has been held successfully</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/06/23/the-second-dubbo-shanghai-meetup-has-been-held-successfully/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/06/23/the-second-dubbo-shanghai-meetup-has-been-held-successfully/</guid><description>&lt;p>The sencond Dubbo meetup has successfully been held in Shanghai, over 700 people submitted registration, and over 300 were present, more than 10,000 watched the live online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please enjoy the slides of the topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Jerrick Zhu: Dubbo Status and Roadmap (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-status-and-roadmap.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mercy Ma: Dubbo Cloud Native Practices and Thoughts (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-cloud-native-practices-and-thoughts.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ping Guo: Nacos Open Source Initiative (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/nacos-open-source-initiative.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zhiwei Pan: Dubbo Practices on Internet Finance Industries (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-practices-on-internet-finance-industries.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The first Dubbo meetup has been held in Beijing</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/12/the-first-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-beijing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/12/the-first-dubbo-meetup-has-been-held-in-beijing/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first Dubbo meetup has successfully been held in Beijing, over 400+ people were present. What a great event!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please enjoy the slides of the topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ian Luo: Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s present and future (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/dubbo-present-and-future.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jun Liu: Introduction to the 4th Aliware Performance Challenge (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/introduction-to-4th-aliware-performance-challenge.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zhixuan Chen: Quickly building Microservice with Dubbo and Spring-boot (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/quickly-building-microservice-with-dubbo-and-springboot.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Xin Wang: Dubbo and Weidian&amp;rsquo;s Practice on Microservice Architecture (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/dubbo-and-weidian's-practice-on-microservice-architecture.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The ApacheCon NA schedule has been announced</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/02/the-apachecon-na-schedule-has-been-announced/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/02/the-apachecon-na-schedule-has-been-announced/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ian Luo(PMC) and Jun Liu(PMC) will talk about &amp;ldquo;Introducing Apache Dubbo(Incubating): What is Dubbo and How it Works&amp;rdquo; at ApacheCon NA this year in Montréal! Please check out the schedule &lt;a href="https://apachecon.dukecon.org/acna/2018/#/scheduledEvent/b8db9dc580d85853f">here&lt;/a> and register &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/apachecon-north-america-2018-registration-43200327342">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The GSoC(Google Summer of Code) 2018</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/25/the-gsocgoogle-summer-of-code-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/25/the-gsocgoogle-summer-of-code-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>The GSoC(Google Summer of Code) 2018 projects has been announced, Raghu Reddy&amp;rsquo;s project &amp;ldquo;Extending Serialization protocols support for Apache Dubbo&amp;rdquo; has been &lt;a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/projects/#4747840161579008">accepted&lt;/a>! Congratulations!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo roadmap is announced in QCon Beijing 2018</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/22/dubbo-roadmap-is-announced-in-qcon-beijing-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/22/dubbo-roadmap-is-announced-in-qcon-beijing-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ian Luo has delivered a great talk at QCon Beijing 2018, where the roadmap of Dubbo has also be announced. Please enjoy the &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/qcon2018/dubbo-present-and-future.pdf">slides&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>