<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Case on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/user-case/</link><description>Recent content in User Case on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/user-case/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dingxiaomi Upgrades to Triple Protocol</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/dingxiaomi-upgrades-to-triple-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/dingxiaomi-upgrades-to-triple-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alibaba Cloud - DAMO Academy - Cloud Xiaomi conversational robot product is based on deep machine learning technology, natural language understanding technology, and dialogue management technology, providing enterprises with multi-engine, multi-channel, and multi-modal conversational robot services. In 2017, Cloud Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s conversational robot started public testing on the public cloud, and continuously expanded in hybrid cloud scenarios. To ensure efficiency and stability in public and hybrid cloud releases, we adopted a major version iteration every 1-2 months after much consideration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Xiaomi's Collaboration with the Dubbo Community</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/xiaomis-collaboration-with-the-dubbo-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/xiaomis-collaboration-with-the-dubbo-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>Xiaomi is devoted to making continuous contributions to the open-source community. Since the introduction of Dubbo3, internal projects are rapidly upgrading to the latest version of Dubbo. Currently, the number of instances has been upgraded to a certain proportion. Not only have performance improvements been seen, but services are also running smoothly with improvements in availability. Statistics provide proof that Dubbo’s switch from API-level discovery to application-level discovery has improved the availability and reliability of service discovery, leading to lower operation costs. In addition, using ProtoBuf for serialization and deserialization has reduced the data exchange size. Lastly, full compatibility with gRPC provides convenience to Xiaomi’s multi-language development environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Migration Journey of Ping An Health to Dubbo3</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/the-migration-journey-of-ping-an-health-to-dubbo3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/01/15/the-migration-journey-of-ping-an-health-to-dubbo3/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="1-background">1 Background&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Our company has used Dubbo as a microservice framework since 2015. When the community launched Dubbo3, we immediately followed suit and conducted in-depth research. We found that the application/instance-level service registration and discovery model of Dubbo3 could alleviate some pressure faced by our current registration center, addressing stability and security issues. At the same time, Dubbo3 has upgraded service governance, aligning with cloud-native architecture, and is backward compatible with Dubbo2, which lowers the cost and risk of upgrading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First National Government-Enterprise Procurement Cloud Platform: The Mixed Cloud Cross-Network Solution Practice of Zhengcai Cloud</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/03/22/the-first-national-government-enterprise-procurement-cloud-platform-the-mixed-cloud-cross-network-solution-practice-of-zhengcai-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/03/22/the-first-national-government-enterprise-procurement-cloud-platform-the-mixed-cloud-cross-network-solution-practice-of-zhengcai-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>For companies with a cloud-island business structure, the cloud platform is an internal, fully controllable local area network, while the island end is an independent internal network with its own security network policy. When cloud-island communication is required, certain ports need to be opened based on demand and customer requirements, which incurs costs and is not completely controllable. If the demand for cross-network communication increases, it will gradually become a pain point. If a transparent cross-network transmission network can be established, along with good top-level design, a better balance can be sought in business support, security control, and operational costs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>