<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Core Advantages on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/</link><description>Recent content in Core Advantages on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick and Easy to Use</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/usability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/usability/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether you are planning to adopt a microservices architecture to develop a new business system or preparing to migrate an existing business from a monolithic architecture to a microservices architecture, the Dubbo framework can help you. Dubbo makes microservices development very easy, allowing you to choose multiple programming languages, use any communication protocol, and it also provides a series of development and testing tools for microservices scenarios to help improve development efficiency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultra-high performance</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/performance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo is designed to address Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s large-scale e-commerce microservice cluster practices and has been tested in tens of thousands to millions of microservice practices in leading enterprises across various industries over the years. Therefore, Dubbo has unparalleled advantages in communication performance and stability, making it very suitable for building nearly infinitely scalable microservice clusters. This is also a significant advantage of Dubbo over many similar products in the industry from a practical perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Service Governance</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/governance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="traffic-control">Traffic Control&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Beyond address discovery and load balancing mechanisms, Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s rich traffic control rules can manage the flow direction and API calls between services. Based on these rules, you can dynamically adjust service behaviors such as timeout periods, retry counts, and rate limiting parameters during runtime. By controlling traffic distribution, you can achieve A/B testing, canary releases, multi-version traffic allocation by ratio, conditional routing, black and white lists, etc., thereby improving system stability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Production Environment Verification</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/production-ready/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/what/advantages/production-ready/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an international open-source project with tens of thousands of enterprise users. It has been tested in large-scale cluster production environments for many years, influencing millions of developers and driving the development of a large microservices open-source ecosystem. Dubbo was incubated from enterprise practices and then open-sourced, quickly achieving success in the open-source community. A large number of production practice users are the core driving force for Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s long-term advancement, stability, and activity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>