<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Improve service security on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/</link><description>Recent content in Improve service security on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dubbo Class Inspection Mechanism</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/class-check/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/class-check/</guid><description>Supported versions Dubbo &amp;gt;= 3.1.6
Scope of application Currently, the serialization check supports Hessian2, Fastjson2 serialization and generalized calls. Other serialization methods are not currently supported.
configuration method 1. Check mode The inspection mode is divided into three levels: STRICT strict inspection, WARN warning, DISABLED disabled. STRICT Strict checks: disallow deserialization of all classes that are not in the allowed serialization list (whitelist). WARN warning: only prohibits serialization of all classes in the disallowed serialization list (blacklist), and alerts through logs when deserializing classes that are not in the allowed serialization list (whitelist).</description></item><item><title>TLS Support</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/tls/</guid><description>Feature description Both the built-in Dubbo Netty Server and the newly introduced gRPC protocol provide a TLS-based secure link transmission mechanism.
There is a unified entry for TLS configuration.
scenes to be used Users who require encryption for the entire link can use TLS.
Reference use case https://github.com/apache/dubbo-samples/tree/master/dubbo-samples-ssl
How to use Provider side SslConfig sslConfig = new SslConfig(); sslConfig.setServerKeyCertChainPath(&amp;#34;path to cert&amp;#34;); sslConfig.setServerPrivateKeyPath(args[1]); // If two-way cert authentication is enabled if (mutualTls) { sslConfig.</description></item><item><title>Access Control</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/token-authorization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/token-authorization/</guid><description>Feature description Control authority in the registration center through token verification to decide whether to issue tokens to consumers, can prevent consumers from bypassing the registry to access the provider, In addition, the authorization method can be flexibly changed through the registration center without modifying or upgrading the provider.
scenes to be used To a certain extent, the trusted authentication of the client and the server is realized, preventing any client from being able to access, and reducing the risk of security problems.</description></item><item><title>Service Authentication</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/auth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/advanced-features-and-usage/security/auth/</guid><description>Feature description Security-sensitive businesses like payments may have a need to limit anonymous calls. In terms of security enhancement, 2.7.5 introduces the authentication and authentication mechanism based on the AK/SK mechanism, and introduces the authentication service center. The main principle is that when the consumer requests a service that requires authentication, it will pass SK, request Data, timestamps, parameters and other information to generate the corresponding request signature, which is carried to the peer end through Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s Attahcment mechanism for signature verification, and business logic processing is performed only after the signature verification is passed.</description></item></channel></rss>