<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Traffic Management on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/</link><description>Recent content in Traffic Management on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adjust traffic distribution by weight</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/weight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/weight/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of adjusting traffic distribution by weight, and can dynamically adjust traffic distribution by weight without restarting the application.
Dubbo can adjust traffic distribution by weight through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully
Background Information In the case of different machine performance, the load of different machines needs to be evaluated systematically, and some machines need to be downgraded.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic adjustment of service timeout</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/timeout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/timeout/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of dynamically adjusting the timeout period, which can dynamically adjust the service timeout period without restarting the application.
Dubbo can dynamically adjust the timeout time through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully
Background Information Various timeout configurations are encountered in daily work.</description></item><item><title>Request Routing</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-routing/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of dynamically creating conditional routing, which can route according to the request initiator and method without restarting the application.
Dubbo can implement dynamic routing according to request conditions through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully</description></item><item><title>Same computer room/area priority</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/zone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/zone/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service management capability of dynamically configuring the priority of the same computer room/region, and can dynamically configure the priority of the same computer room/region without restarting the application.
Dubbo can be configured through XML, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration in the same computer room/area first. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully</description></item><item><title>Temporarily kick out the problem service instance</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/isolation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/isolation/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service management capability of temporarily removing problematic service instances, which can temporarily remove problematic service instances without restarting the application.
Dubbo can temporarily remove problem service instances through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully
Background Information When the service is running online, it is inevitable that some nodes have problems.</description></item><item><title>Traffic Grayscale</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-gray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-gray/</guid><description>Dubbo provides traffic grayscale service management capabilities, and can configure label routing rules and conditional routing to achieve grayscale publishing without restarting the application.
Dubbo can achieve traffic grayscale through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully
Background Information Scenarios of demand changes and version iterations will be encountered during product development.</description></item><item><title>Traffic Isolation</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-condition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-condition/</guid><description>Dubbo provides the service management capability of dynamic traffic isolation, which can dynamically isolate traffic without restarting the application.
Dubbo can implement traffic isolation through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document Configuration
before the start Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully
Background Information If multiple versions of an application run simultaneously online and are deployed in different environments, such as daily environments and special environments, you can use label routing to isolate the traffic of different versions in different environments, and the order traffic of flash sales or orders from different channels Routing to special environments, routing normal traffic to everyday environments.</description></item></channel></rss>