<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Traffic Management on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/</link><description>Recent content in Traffic Management on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adjust traffic distribution by weight</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/weight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/weight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of adjusting traffic distribution by weight, and can dynamically adjust traffic distribution by weight without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can adjust traffic distribution by weight through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-information">Background Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the case of different machine performance, the load of different machines needs to be evaluated systematically, and some machines need to be downgraded. By adjusting the traffic ratio of the machine by weight, the performance of the machine can be reasonably evaluated.
Certain services will face traffic shocks. In order to ensure the availability of core services, some services need to be downgraded. Adjust traffic distribution by weight to avoid faults caused by traffic impact.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic adjustment of service timeout</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/timeout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/timeout/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of dynamically adjusting the timeout period, which can dynamically adjust the service timeout period without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can dynamically adjust the timeout time through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-information">Background Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Various timeout configurations are encountered in daily work. After the business logic is changed, the existing call relationship may need to be adjusted continuously with the development of the business, and the change of the response time of the corresponding service interface may not be determined until it goes online. Dubbo-Admin provides a dynamic timeout configuration capability, which can help you quickly and dynamically adjust the interface timeout time to improve service availability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Request Routing</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-routing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service governance capability of dynamically creating conditional routing, which can route according to the request initiator and method without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can implement dynamic routing according to request conditions through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Same computer room/area priority</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/zone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/zone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service management capability of dynamically configuring the priority of the same computer room/region, and can dynamically configure the priority of the same computer room/region without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can be configured through XML, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration in the same computer room/area first. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temporarily kick out the problem service instance</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/isolation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/isolation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service management capability of temporarily removing problematic service instances, which can temporarily remove problematic service instances without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can temporarily remove problem service instances through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-information">Background Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When the service is running online, it is inevitable that some nodes have problems. In order not to affect the normal operation of the overall service, the service instance with the problem needs to be temporarily offline. Dubbo-Admin provides the ability to temporarily remove problematic service instances, which can help you temporarily offline problematic service instances without affecting the operation of the overall service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traffic Grayscale</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-gray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-gray/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides traffic grayscale service management capabilities, and can configure label routing rules and conditional routing to achieve grayscale publishing without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can achieve traffic grayscale through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-information">Background Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Scenarios of demand changes and version iterations will be encountered during product development. In order to take into account both demand changes and system stability, the release should be as smooth as possible, and the number of affected people should be small to large, and roll back immediately if there is a problem. Dubbo-Admin provides dynamic traffic grayscale capabilities, which can help you bid for new services, release services smoothly, and improve service stability and availability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traffic Isolation</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-condition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/traffic-management/traffic-condition/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides the service management capability of dynamic traffic isolation, which can dynamically isolate traffic without restarting the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo can implement traffic isolation through XML configuration, annotation configuration, and dynamic configuration. Here we mainly introduce the dynamic configuration method. For other configuration methods, please refer to the old document &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/zh-cn/docsv2.7/user/configuration/">Configuration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-the-start">before the start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please make sure to run Dubbo-Admin successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-information">Background Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If multiple versions of an application run simultaneously online and are deployed in different environments, such as daily environments and special environments, you can use label routing to isolate the traffic of different versions in different environments, and the order traffic of flash sales or orders from different channels Routing to special environments, routing normal traffic to everyday environments. Even if the special environment is abnormal, the traffic that should have entered the special environment will not enter the daily environment, and will not affect the use of the daily environment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>