<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Start on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Start on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Develop RPC Server &amp; RPC Client</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/rpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/rpc/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based on the Triple protocol defined by Dubbo, you can easily write browser and gRPC compatible RPC services that run on both HTTP/1 and HTTP/2 simultaneously. The Dubbo Go SDK supports defining services using IDL or programming language-specific methods and provides a lightweight API for publishing or invoking these services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This example demonstrates the RPC communication pattern based on the Triple protocol. The example uses Protocol Buffer to define the RPC service and demonstrates the processes of code generation, service publishing, and service access.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Developing Microservices</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/microservices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/golang-sdk/quickstart/microservices/</guid><description>&lt;p>This example demonstrates how to develop microservice applications using dubbo-go, adding core microservice capabilities such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic control to the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this example, we will continue to use Protobuf to develop the microservice application. Please refer to &lt;a href="../rpc">Develop RPC Server and RPC Client&lt;/a> to learn how to install necessary plugins like protoc and protoc-gen-go-triple.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quick-run-example">Quick Run Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="download-example-source-code">Download Example Source Code&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We maintain a series of dubbo-go usage examples in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/apache/dubbo-go-samples/" target="_blank">apache/dubbo-go-samples&lt;/a> repository to help users quickly learn how to use dubbo-go.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>