<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Start on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Start on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a microservice application based on Spring Boot</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/starter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/starter/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following document will guide you in creating a Dubbo application based on Spring Boot from scratch, configuring microservice foundational capabilities such as the Triple communication protocol and service discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quickly-create-an-application">Quickly Create an Application&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Create a Dubbo microservice application by accessing &lt;a href="https://start.dubbo.apache.org" target="_blank">start.dubbo.apache.org&lt;/a>. Add components as shown in the image below, and you can quickly create a Dubbo application in seconds. Download and unzip the generated sample application.&lt;/p>
&lt;img style="max-width:800px;height:auto;margin-bottom:10px;" alt="Project Structure Screenshot" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/v3/quickstart/start.jpg"/>


&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Directly Use the Official Sample&lt;/h4>

 &lt;p>You can also download the official pre-prepared sample project directly:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quick Deployment of Dubbo Applications</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/quick-start/deploy/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the previous article, we created a Dubbo application from scratch and detailed its code structure. Next, we will learn how to deploy this Dubbo application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article will explain the deployment of Dubbo applications based on a Kubernetes cluster, and the deployment architecture is shown in the diagram below.
&lt;img alt="Dubbo+Kubernetes+Nacos Deployment Architecture">&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>

 In real-world usage, the deployment environment may vary widely, including Kubernetes Services, Service Mesh, virtual machines, and more. Please refer to &lt;a href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/">Deployment Documentation&lt;/a> for more detailed content.

&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Dubbo community provides tools and solutions to simplify the packaging and deployment process in the entire Kubernetes environment. Therefore, we need to install the relevant tools before we begin.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>