<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Dubbo – Security Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/security-vulnerabilities/</link><description>Recent content in Security Vulnerabilities on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/security-vulnerabilities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Serialization Protocol Security</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/1/01/01/serialization-protocol-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/1/01/01/serialization-protocol-security/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dubbo 3 has enhanced the security aspects of serialization protocols and recommends using the Triple protocol in non-Wrapper mode. This protocol is secure by default but requires developers to write IDL files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Triple protocol&amp;rsquo;s Wrapper mode, compatibility with other serialization data is allowed, offering good compatibility. However, other protocols may have deserialization security flaws. For the Hessian2 protocol, users who require high-security attributes should enable whitelist mode according to the sample code. The framework will enable blacklist mode by default to block malicious calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using other serialization protocols is not recommended. When an attacker can access the Provider interface, security flaws in other serialization protocols may lead to command execution through the Provider interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you must use other serialization protocols and wish to maintain some level of security, you should enable the Token authentication mechanism. This will prevent threats to the Provider&amp;rsquo;s security from unauthenticated and untrusted request sources. When enabling Token authentication, you should also enable the authentication feature in the registry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="notice">Notice&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following serializations are proved that not safe enough to transfer on network and not recommend to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>native-hessian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>native-java (Java ObjectOutputStream and ObjectInputStream)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>