<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node.js on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/node.js/</link><description>Recent content in Node.js on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/node.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Dubbo's First Node.js 3.0-alpha Version Officially Released</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/07/apache-dubbos-first-node.js-3.0-alpha-version-officially-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/07/apache-dubbos-first-node.js-3.0-alpha-version-officially-released/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="about-apache-dubbo3">About Apache Dubbo3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an easy-to-use, high-performance WEB and RPC framework, providing capabilities, tools, and best practices for creating enterprise-level microservices including service discovery, traffic governance, observability, and authentication. After several years of development, Dubbo3 has been widely promoted across Alibaba Group’s business lines, successfully replacing the HSF framework that had been in operation for years; meanwhile, the multi-language ecosystem of Dubbo3 has also developed rapidly, currently covering:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Cross-Language Calls to dubbo2.js</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/from-cross-language-calls-to-dubbo2.js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/14/from-cross-language-calls-to-dubbo2.js/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/dubbo2.js">dubbo2.js&lt;/a> is a Node.js Dubbo client contributed by &lt;a href="https://www.qianmi.com/">Qianmi&lt;/a> to the Dubbo community. It provides support for the native Dubbo protocol in Node.js, making RPC calls between Node.js and Java, two heterogeneous languages, convenient and efficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="cross-language-calls-in-microservices">Cross-Language Calls in Microservices&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Microservice architecture has become the trend in today’s internet architecture, and discussions about microservices occupy most of the various technical conferences. The most widely used service governance framework in China is undoubtedly Dubbo, an open-source project from Alibaba. Qianmi has also chosen Dubbo as its microservice governance framework. On the other hand, like most internet companies, Qianmi has a diverse range of development languages, with most backend services supported by Java, while each business line has the freedom to choose its own development language, leading to issues of calling Node.js, Python, and Go in a multi-language environment. Cross-language invocation is a broad and challenging topic, and several solutions frequently mentioned in the industry are as follows:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>