<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gateway on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/gateway/</link><description>Recent content in Gateway on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:53:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Apache APISIX to Proxy Dubbo Services (Dubbo Protocol)</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/04/25/using-apache-apisix-to-proxy-dubbo-services-dubbo-protocol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/04/25/using-apache-apisix-to-proxy-dubbo-services-dubbo-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>

 This article is only applicable to the Dubbo protocol communication scenario. If you are a Dubbo3 user, it is recommended to use the triple protocol. Please refer to &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/04/22/using-apache-apisix-to-proxy-dubbo-services-triple-protocol/">Using Apache APISIX to Proxy Dubbo Services (Triple Protocol)&lt;/a> for specific examples.

&lt;/div>

&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://apisix.apache.org/">Apache APISIX&lt;/a> is a top-level open-source project of the Apache Software Foundation and the most active open-source gateway project currently. As a dynamic, real-time, high-performance open-source API gateway, Apache APISIX provides rich traffic management features such as load balancing, dynamic upstream, gray release, service circuit breaking, authentication, and observability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Proxy Dubbo Services via Higress Gateway</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/04/01/how-to-proxy-dubbo-services-via-higress-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/04/01/how-to-proxy-dubbo-services-via-higress-gateway/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>

 This article is only applicable to Dubbo protocol communication scenarios. If you are a Dubbo3 user, it is recommended to use the triple protocol. Please refer to &lt;a href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/gateway/triple/">Use Apache APISIX to Proxy Dubbo Services (triple protocol)&lt;/a> for specific examples.

&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Higress provides the capability to convert from HTTP protocol to Dubbo protocol. Users can expose a Dubbo service as an HTTP interface by configuring protocol conversion, thus allowing HTTP requests to invoke Dubbo interfaces. This article introduces how to configure HTTP to Dubbo protocol conversion using Higress through an example. The example guides you to easily deploy a Nacos server and a Dubbo service, then forwards HTTP requests to the Dubbo service registered in Nacos through Ingress, and accomplishes HTTP calls to the Dubbo service through Higress&amp;rsquo;s protocol conversion capability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Proxy Dubbo Services through Apache ShenYu Gateway</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/05/04/how-to-proxy-dubbo-services-through-apache-shenyu-gateway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/05/04/how-to-proxy-dubbo-services-through-apache-shenyu-gateway/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/shenyu-dubbo/ApacheShenYu-Dubbo-en.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Apache ShenYu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/shenyu-dubbo/shenyu.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shenyu.apache.org/docs/index">Apache ShenYu(Incubating)&lt;/a> is an asynchronous, high-performance, cross-language, and responsive &lt;code>API&lt;/code> gateway. Compatible with various mainstream framework systems, it supports hot swapping, and users can customize development to meet various current and future needs through large-scale scenario testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May 2021, &lt;code>ShenYu&lt;/code> was donated to the &lt;code>Apache&lt;/code> Software Foundation, which was fully approved by the Apache Foundation and successfully entered the incubator.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Apache Dubbo&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Apache Dubbo&lt;/code> is a microservices development framework that provides two key capabilities: &lt;code>RPC&lt;/code> communication and microservice governance. This means that microservices developed using &lt;code>Dubbo&lt;/code> will have remote discovery and communication capabilities among themselves, while utilizing the rich service governance capabilities provided by Dubbo to implement service governance requirements such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic scheduling. Additionally, &lt;code>Dubbo&lt;/code> is highly extensible, allowing users to customize their implementations at almost any function point to change the default behavior of the framework to meet their business needs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>