<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spring-Cloud on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/spring-cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Spring-Cloud on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 09:30:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/spring-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Practices for Microservices: Zero Refactoring to Achieve Interoperability Between Spring Cloud and Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/07/best-practices-for-microservices-zero-refactoring-to-achieve-interoperability-between-spring-cloud-and-apache-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/07/best-practices-for-microservices-zero-refactoring-to-achieve-interoperability-between-spring-cloud-and-apache-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>This article uses real projects and code as examples, demonstrating step by step how to achieve interoperability between the Apache Dubbo system and the Spring Cloud system with minimal cost, enabling hybrid deployment and migration of different microservice systems, helping you solve practical architectural and business issues.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-and-goals">Background and Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are facing the following business scenarios during microservice development, this article can help you:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You already have a microservice application built on Dubbo, and now you need to publish some services through REST HTTP without changing the code, just adding some configurations and annotations for the pre-written Dubbo services.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You have a microservice system based on Spring Cloud and later built a set of microservices on Dubbo. You want both systems to coexist, requiring mutual access to services published by each other.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Due to historical reasons, you are planning to migrate from one microservice system to another, ensuring a smooth transition in the process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="image.png" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/2023/9/springcloud/img.png">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>