<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security Notice on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/</link><description>Recent content in Security Notice on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Serialization Security</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/serialization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/serialization/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dubbo supports the extension of serialization protocols. In theory, users can enable any serialization protocol based on this extension mechanism. This brings great flexibility, but at the same time, users must be aware of the hidden security risks.
Data deserialization is the link most easily exploited by attackers, who use it to perform RCE attacks to steal or destroy server-side data.
Before switching serialization protocols or implementations, users should fully investigate the security guarantees of the target serialization protocol and its framework implementation, and set up corresponding security measures in advance (such as setting up a black/white list).
The Dubbo framework itself cannot directly guarantee the security of the target serialization mechanism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RPC Protocol Security</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/protocol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo supports the extension of the RPC protocol. In theory, users can enable any RPC protocol based on this extension mechanism. This brings great flexibility, but at the same time, users must be aware of the hidden security risks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The serialization protocols provided by the official version of Dubbo 2.7 are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dubbo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RMI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hessian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Http/Rest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webservice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thrift&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gRPC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>…&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Starting from Dubbo 3.0, only the following serialization protocol support is provided by default:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Registration Center Security</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/registry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/registry/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo supports the extension of the registration center. In theory, users can enable any registration center based on this extension mechanism. This brings great flexibility, but at the same time, users must be aware of the hidden security risks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The official version of Dubbo 2.7 provides the following registration centers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zookeeper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Redis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nacos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Etcd&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consul&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Starting from Dubbo 3.0, only the following registration centers are supported by default:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zookeeper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nacos&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For the registration center, Dubbo can only fully trust the data pushed by it. Therefore, if there is a security vulnerability in the registration center, the Dubbo service may be maliciously registered or data may be maliciously pushed, resulting in the service being attacked.
Therefore, in order to ensure the security of the registration center, Dubbo officially recommends that you:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Admin Security</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/admin/</guid><description>&lt;p>In order to facilitate the use of Dubbo, Dubbo officially provides the Dubbo Admin console to facilitate the management of Dubbo applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="risk">Risk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dubbo Admin has query and call permissions for the entire cluster by default, so it needs to be used with more caution in the online environment.
In addition, in order to reduce the risk of arbitrary access to Dubbo Admin, Dubbo Admin also provides a simple authentication mechanism.
To make Dubbo Admin more secure, please refer to the documentation below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Log4j vulnerability impact</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/log4j/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/notices/log4j/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, the mainstream logging component &lt;a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/">log4j2&lt;/a> broke out &lt;a href="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2021-44228">security vulnerability CVE-2021-44228&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following is a summary of the impact of vulnerability CVE-2021-44228 on the Apache Dubbo framework and user response guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dubbo-scope-of-influence">Dubbo scope of influence&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>**This vulnerability has no impact on the security of Dubbo framework. **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo itself does not rely heavily on the log4j2 framework, nor does it bring log4j2 to business projects through dependency transfer. Therefore, users who are using Dubbo 2.7.x, 3.0.x and other versions do not need to be forced to upgrade the Dubbo version.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>