<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microservice Governance on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/</link><description>Recent content in Microservice Governance on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transaction Management</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/transaction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/transaction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-seata">What is Seata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Seata is an open source distributed transaction solution dedicated to providing high-performance and easy-to-use distributed transaction services. Seata will provide users with AT, TCC, SAGA and XA transaction modes to create a one-stop distributed solution for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-example-architecture-description">1. Example architecture description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The user purchases commodity business, and the whole business includes 3 microservices:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Inventory service: deduction of the inventory quantity of a given item.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Order service: Generate orders based on purchase requests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Account Services: deduction of the user account amount.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="image.png" src="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/imgs/docs3-v2/java-sdk/seata/transaction-1.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Current Limit Downgrade</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/rate-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/tasks/ecosystem/rate-limit/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-sentinel">What is Sentinel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the popularity of microservices, the stability between services and services has become more and more important. Sentinel is a traffic management component for distributed, multilingual and heterogeneous service architectures. It mainly uses traffic as the entry point, from traffic routing, traffic control, traffic shaping, fuse downgrade, system adaptive overload protection, hotspot traffic protection, etc. dimensions to help developers ensure the stability of microservices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-example-architecture-description">1. Example architecture description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Interface definition:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>