<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Committer Guide on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/</link><description>Recent content in Committer Guide on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Committer Guide</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/new-committer-guide_dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/new-committer-guide_dev/</guid><description>First: How to become a committer Initial committers at the project incubator stage At the project incubator stage, there will be an initial committers list in the proposal of the incubator project. Confirm that you are one of the initial committers. After the vote is passed in the Apache incubator community, these committers can start preparing their account. See incubator wiki for details.
The active contributor is elected as a committer At the late development stage, an active contributor can be elected as a committer.</description></item><item><title>Release Guide</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/release-guide_dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/release-guide_dev/</guid><description>Understanding the Apache Release Cycle In general, Source Release is the key and the required content of Apache. But Binary Release is optional, Dubbo can choose whether to release binary packages to the Apache repository or to the Maven central repository.
Please refer to the following links for more information on ASF&amp;rsquo;s release guide:
Apache Release Guide Apache Release Policy Maven Release Info Preparation of Local Building Environment Mainly including the related preparation of signature utilities and Maven repository certification</description></item><item><title>Label an Issue</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/label-an-issue-guide_dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/label-an-issue-guide_dev/</guid><description>If you are handling an issue, remember to mark the issue cearly with one or more labels whenever you think it&amp;rsquo;s meaningful. With labels on, other developers can easily recognize problems, classify them or track progress.
For issues or pull requests that need coding and further version release to fix, you should always mark it with a milestone.
Some frequently used labels:
Help Wanted
help wanted good first issue Prority</description></item><item><title>Website Guide</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/website-guide_dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/website-guide_dev/</guid><description> The website repository of Apache Dubbo is https://github.com/apache/dubbo-website After building the website, it&amp;rsquo;ll be published to dubbo.apache.org automatically, you can also trigger it manually via https://selfserve.apache.org (need to login with Apache account)</description></item><item><title>Apache Official Dubbo Page Maintenance</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/apache-dubbo-page_dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs/contribution-guidelines/committer/apache-dubbo-page_dev/</guid><description>Apache has an official website that maintains information about all incubation projects. Each incubation project has an information page under this website. Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s information page address is https://incubator.apache.org/projects/dubbo.html.
When the project has undergone major changes, such as the addition of a new committer, the election of a new PMC, or a new version of Release, etc, these updates need to be maintained on this page. The project address for this official website is https://svn.</description></item></channel></rss>