<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Preface on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/</link><description>Recent content in Preface on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Dubbo-go</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/what/</guid><description>Apache/Dubbo-go (github.com/apache/dubbo-go)
It is a distributed RPC framework; it is the Go language implementation of Apache/Dubbo. It aims to provide developers with a convenient microservice application development experience.
Dubbo-go builds a bridge between Java and Go languages, interconnects with the gRPC/Dubbo/SpringCloud ecology, and relies on the Go language ecology to explore the technical dividends of the cloud-native era.</description></item><item><title>New Features of Dubbo-go 3.0</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/3.0_feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/3.0_feature/</guid><description>1. Triple protocol 1.1 Overview communication level
The Triple protocol, also known as the Dubbo3 protocol, is an extension protocol based on the HTTP2 + gRPC protocol, adding specific fields and logic, ensuring interoperability with the native gRPC protocol. On this basis, Triple&amp;rsquo;s new protocol will more natively support Dubbo service governance capabilities. And supports streaming RPC calls.
In simple terms, it can be understood as Triple = gRPC + Dubbo</description></item><item><title>Dubbo-go Samples</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/samples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/golang-sdk/preface/samples/</guid><description>In order to facilitate the use of Dubbogo framework users, we provide the Samples repository for user reference:
[Dubbo-go-samples warehouse address]
1. Examples contained in the Samples repository config-api: use API for configuration initialization configcenter: Use different configuration centers, currently supports three types: zookeeper, apollo, and nacos context: how to use context to pass attachment direct: direct connection mode game: game service example generic: generalized call rpc: RPC call example, including Triple, Dubbo and other protocols and cross-language/gRPC interoperability examples helloworld: RPC call entry example logger: log example registry: Show the docking with different registry centers, including zk, nacos, etcd metrics: data reporting filter: Examples of using provided filters and custom filters registry/servicediscovery: application-level service discovery example router: routing example tracing: link tracing example 2.</description></item></channel></rss>