<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quickly Create Applications on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/</link><description>Recent content in Quickly Create Applications on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring Boot</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/springboot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/springboot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo provides full support for the Spring framework, and we recommend using the official &lt;code>dubbo-spring-boot-starter&lt;/code> for efficient development of Dubbo microservice applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-a-project">Creating a Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The fastest way to create a Dubbo application is to use the official project scaffold tool - &lt;a href="https://start.dubbo.apache.org" target="_blank">start.dubbo.apache.org&lt;/a> online service. It helps developers create Spring Boot structured applications and automatically manage dependencies like &lt;code>dubbo-spring-boot-starter&lt;/code> along with necessary configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, Jetbrain also provides an Apache Dubbo project plugin for quickly creating Dubbo Spring Boot projects, which is on par with start.dubbo.apache.org. For specific installation and usage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Developing Dubbo Applications Using Native APIs</title><link>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cn.dubbo.apache.org/en/overview/mannual/java-sdk/tasks/develop/api/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may have noticed that most of the functions and examples in the documentation are based on the Spring Boot model, but Spring Boot or Spring is merely one application or microservice development model adapted by Dubbo. &lt;strong>As an RPC framework, Dubbo defines a comprehensive set of API interfaces, enabling us to develop Dubbo applications based on the native APIs&lt;/strong>. Business scenarios that can be achieved with pure APIs include:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>