<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2 - Routing on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/</link><description>Recent content in 2 - Routing on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2-1 - Routing execution failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/1/</guid><description>Routing address execution failed</description></item><item><title>2-11 - Label Routing Rules Illegal</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/11/</guid><description>Possible Reason The label routing rule configured by the user is invalid. The label routing address configured by the user is invalid. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Refer to the community label routing configuration specification, and check the label routing configuration.</description></item><item><title>2-12 - Label route acquisition provider application name is empty</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/12/</guid><description>Possible Reason The label route obtains the provider application name from the push provider address list and is empty. Troubleshooting and resolution steps This exception is an exception of the Dubbo framework itself. Please file an issue in the community and provide the environment site information and reproduction steps.</description></item><item><title>2-13 - Failed to receive and load mesh routing rules</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/13/</guid><description>Possible Reason The rules of the mesh routing configuration are illegal, and the loading is abnormal. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the mesh routing rule configuration. &amp;ldquo;Mesh Example&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>2-15 - Routing rule parsing failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/15/</guid><description>Possible Reason The routing rule configured by the user is invalid. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the configured routing rules.</description></item><item><title>2-15 - Script route execution failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/14/</guid><description>Possible Reason Script routing rules are illegal, resulting in rule parsing failure. Dubbo framework failed to execute the script. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check that the script is written according to the specification.</description></item><item><title>2-16 - Request retries failed multiple times</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/16/</guid><description>Possible Reason The provider is abnormal, causing the consumer to retry and fail many times. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the health status of the provider.</description></item><item><title>2-17 - mock request failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/17/</guid><description>Possible Reason Configured mandatory mock, suggestive log. Executing the mock request is abnormal. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether mandatory mock is configured. Check whether the mock response is normal.</description></item><item><title>2-18 - Mesh routing rules are not monitored</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/18/</guid><description>Possible Reason Mesh delivered routing rules, but the rules were not monitored. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the mesh routing rule configuration complies with the specification.</description></item><item><title>2-19 - Asynchronous request failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/19/</guid><description>Possible Reason The provider is abnormal, causing the asynchronous request of the consumer to fail. The network is abnormal, causing the asynchronous request of the consumer to fail. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the health status of the provider. Check the network status.</description></item><item><title>2-2 - No Provider available (address not found)</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/2/</guid><description>Possible Reason There may be several situations at this time:
The Provider service is not started, or the registration center (such as ZooKeeper, Nacos, Consul) is down. There is an error in the service configuration of Dubbo, you must ensure that the service name, group (default is Dubbo), and version are all correct. The accessed environment is wrong: Usually we have multiple environments such as development environment, test environment, and online production environment.</description></item><item><title>2-3 - Routing shutdown failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/3/</guid><description>Possible Reason User-defined routes are not written according to the specification. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Refer to the community SPI extension manual to check user-defined routes, &amp;ldquo;SPI Extension User Manual&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>2-4 - Merger interface failed to load</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/4/</guid><description>Possible Reason Dubbo provides an SPI extension Merger interface that aggregates the responses of all downstream providers. When Dubbo loads the user-defined extension Merger interface, the loading configuration fails. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Refer to the community SPI extension manual to check the implementation of the user-defined extension Merger interface, [&amp;ldquo;SPI Extension User Manual&amp;rdquo;](/zh-cn/overview/mannual/java-sdk/reference-manual /spi/).</description></item><item><title>2-5 - Filter Provider Failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/5/</guid><description>Possible Reason Dubbo will finally select a provider from the provider list to initiate a call during load balancing. During the selection process, the provider list changes, and read-write conflicts occur, resulting in screening exceptions. When the Dubbo retry mechanism fails to call the provider, it will re-screen another provider to initiate the call, and an exception occurs during the re-screening process. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the registry provider list and the availability of the corresponding provider.</description></item><item><title>2-6 - Conditional routing filter provider list is empty</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/6/</guid><description>Possible Reason Conditional routing provider filter condition is empty. Conditional routing filter provider list remains empty under forced downgrade. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Refer to the community request routing example to adjust the conditional routing configuration.</description></item><item><title>2-7 - Conditional routing execution exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/7/</guid><description>Possible Reason Conditional routing rules are not configured according to the specification, resulting in exceptions when executing conditional routing filtering. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Refer to the community request routing example to adjust the conditional routing configuration.</description></item><item><title>2-8 - The provider returned an abnormal response</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/8/</guid><description>Possible Reason The provider&amp;rsquo;s own processing result throws an exception. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the provider program is normal.</description></item><item><title>2-9 - Increase timeout check task failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/9/</guid><description>Possible Reason The Dubbo framework will add a timeout check task to the request call, and the added timeout check task fails. Troubleshooting and resolution steps This exception is an exception of the Dubbo framework itself. Please file an issue in the community and provide the environment site information and reproduction steps.</description></item><item><title>2-10 - Failed to call service provider</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/10/</guid><description>Possible Reason Dubbo failed to call the service provider and started retrying. Dubbo retries to call the service provider and continues to fail. Dubbo retries calling the service provider reaches the upper limit. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check network resources such as time-consuming network connections between consumers and providers. Check whether the corresponding port of the provider can respond normally through telnet or other means. Check that the provider program is functioning properly.</description></item><item><title>2-20 - Failed to get grouped results merged</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/2/20/</guid><description>Possible Reason Failed to get grouped results merged. Troubleshooting and resolution steps When the result is returned, there may be runtime exceptions in business logic, which can be traced according to the number of lines of code specified in the console.</description></item></channel></rss>