<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:06:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Focusing on Stability, Dubbo Java Release Plan Announced</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/10/22/focusing-on-stability-dubbo-java-release-plan-announced/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2022/10/22/focusing-on-stability-dubbo-java-release-plan-announced/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-dubbo">Introduction to Dubbo&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an RPC service development framework designed to address service governance and communication issues in microservice architectures. Official SDK implementations are available in multiple languages, including Java and Golang. Microservices developed with Dubbo possess built-in capabilities for remote address discovery and communication, leveraging Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s rich service governance features to achieve needs such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic scheduling. Dubbo is designed for high extensibility, allowing users to easily implement various customized logic for traffic interception and service selection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apache Dubbo 3.3 Released: Triple X Leads a New Era of Microservices Communication</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/09/11/apache-dubbo-3.3-released-triple-x-leads-a-new-era-of-microservices-communication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2024/09/11/apache-dubbo-3.3-released-triple-x-leads-a-new-era-of-microservices-communication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apache Dubbo has surpassed 40,000 stars, and the team is proud to announce the official release of Dubbo 3.3! As a leading open-source microservices framework, Dubbo has always been committed to providing developers with high-performance, scalable, and flexible solutions for distributed services. The release of Dubbo 3.3, featuring the &lt;strong>Triple X&lt;/strong> upgrade, breaks previous limitations, achieving comprehensive support for both north-south and east-west traffic, and enhancing compatibility with cloud-native architectures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generate Project Scaffolding via Template</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/12/31/generate-project-scaffolding-via-template/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/12/31/generate-project-scaffolding-via-template/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://start.dubbo.apache.org/bootstrap.html" target="_blank">Dubbo Initializer&lt;/a> can be used to quickly generate Java project scaffolding, helping to simplify the setup, basic configuration, and component dependency management of microservice projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Initializer is still being updated, and more support for Dubbo Features will be released gradually.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="choose-dubbo-version">Choose Dubbo Version&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Initializer will use &lt;code>dubbo-spring-boot-starter&lt;/code> to create Spring Boot projects, so we need to first choose the versions of Dubbo and Spring Boot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="initializer-choose-version" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/v3/tasks/develop/initializer-choose-version.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enter-basic-project-information">Enter Basic Project Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Next, fill in the basic project information, including project coordinates, project name, package name, JDK version, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IntelliJ IDEA❤️Apache Dubbo, Official IDEA Plugin Released!</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/23/intellij-idea%EF%B8%8Fapache-dubbo-official-idea-plugin-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/10/23/intellij-idea%EF%B8%8Fapache-dubbo-official-idea-plugin-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>The most popular Java Integrated Development Environment, IntelliJ IDEA, has teamed up with the open-source microservices framework Apache Dubbo community, bringing great news to microservices developers. Alongside IntelliJ IDEA version 2023.2, &lt;strong>Jetbrains officially released a new plugin - Apache Dubbo in Spring Framework&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="IntelliJ IDEA loves️ Apache Dubbo" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/2023/10/plugin/img_6.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This plugin helps developers address Dubbo project initialization issues and facilitates the identification of Dubbo services and their dependencies during the project development process, making microservice development based on Apache Dubbo very simple.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Microservices Forum - See You at the ApacheCon Conference in Beijing on August 19</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/08/07/dubbo-microservices-forum-see-you-at-the-apachecon-conference-in-beijing-on-august-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/08/07/dubbo-microservices-forum-see-you-at-the-apachecon-conference-in-beijing-on-august-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dubbo Microservices Forum will be held on the afternoon of August 19 at the Lihong Huayuan Hotel in Beijing. As a key topic of the CommunityOverCode Asia 2023 (formerly ApacheCon Asia), we will focus on Apache Dubbo and bring you exciting content on the development direction of open-source microservices technology, cloud-native microservices selection, and enterprise practice sharing!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open the &lt;a href="https://www.bagevent.com/event/cocasia-2023">official ticket purchase link&lt;/a>, enter the cocasia discount code for a 20% discount!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GLCC x Apache Dubbo Programming Summer Camp Registration Starts</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/07/05/glcc-x-apache-dubbo-programming-summer-camp-registration-starts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/07/05/glcc-x-apache-dubbo-programming-summer-camp-registration-starts/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background-introduction">Background Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The GitLink Programming Summer Camp (GLCC) is a summer programming activity for university students across the country, organized by the CCF Open Source Development Committee (CCF ODC) under the guidance of the CCF China Computer Federation. The activity will cover nearly a thousand universities and will collaborate with major open-source foundations, open-source companies, open-source communities, and open-source experts. The aim is to encourage young students to improve their technical abilities by participating in real open source software development and to nurture outstanding talents for the open source community. It provides a friendly and open communication platform for young students and hopes to further promote the prosperity and development of the domestic open source community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apache Dubbo Open Source Summer 2023, Contributing to the Community to Win 12,000 in Bonuses</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/05/15/apache-dubbo-open-source-summer-2023-contributing-to-the-community-to-win-12000-in-bonuses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/05/15/apache-dubbo-open-source-summer-2023-contributing-to-the-community-to-win-12000-in-bonuses/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome students to participate in Apache Dubbo Open Source Summer. Community mentors will guide you to &lt;strong>make your code widely reused in society and earn up to 12,000 in bonuses. You can&lt;/strong> also get a job/internship recommendation at your desired company, &lt;strong>gaining money, growth, and value&lt;/strong>. What are you waiting for? Registration is closing soon, join the Apache Dubbo Open Source Summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-ospp-open-source-summer">What is OSPP Open Source Summer?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Open Source Summer is a summer open-source program initiated and supported by the &amp;ldquo;Open Source Software Supply Chain Lighting Project,&amp;rdquo; aimed at encouraging &lt;strong>students&lt;/strong> to actively participate in the development and maintenance of open-source software, promoting the vigorous development of excellent open-source communities, and nurturing more outstanding developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advancing Cloud Native - Dubbo 3.2 Official Release</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/04/15/advancing-cloud-native-dubbo-3.2-official-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2023/04/15/advancing-cloud-native-dubbo-3.2-official-release/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background-introduction">Background Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Apache Dubbo is an RPC service development framework designed to solve service governance and communication issues in microservice architectures, with official SDK implementations in Java, Golang, and other languages. Microservices developed with Dubbo possess inherent capabilities for remote address discovery and communication, leveraging Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s rich service governance features to fulfill service governance needs such as service discovery, load balancing, and traffic management. Dubbo is designed to be highly extensible, allowing users to easily implement various custom logic for traffic interception and location selection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can Apache Dubbo, Now a Decade Old, Ride the Waves Again?</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/01/14/can-apache-dubbo-now-a-decade-old-ride-the-waves-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/01/14/can-apache-dubbo-now-a-decade-old-ride-the-waves-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/dubbo-go/10years/dubbo-home.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout the history of open source in China, it is hard to find a second project as controversial and discussed as Dubbo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, its open source in 2011 filled the gap of RPC frameworks used in production environments, and it was widely adopted upon release; on the other hand, it experienced a halt in maintenance, a restart, donation to the Apache Foundation, and then graduated as a top-level project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Go Review and Outlook</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/01/11/dubbo-go-review-and-outlook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2021/01/11/dubbo-go-review-and-outlook/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo is a high-performance RPC framework open-sourced by Alibaba in 2011, which has significant influence in the Java ecosystem. On May 21, 2019, Dubbo graduated from the Apache Software Foundation and became an Apache Top-Level Project. Currently, the graduated Dubbo project&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem has officially announced the introduction of the Go language, releasing the Dubbogo project. This article is a complete review and genuine outlook of the Dubbogo project, collaboratively completed by Yu Yu from Ant Financial and Fang Yincheng from the Ctrip R&amp;amp;D Department.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Annual Review and Summary of Apache Dubbo from 2019 to 2020</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2020/05/11/annual-review-and-summary-of-apache-dubbo-from-2019-to-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2020/05/11/annual-review-and-summary-of-apache-dubbo-from-2019-to-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thank you all for your attention to the Dubbo community. In this article, we will summarize the achievements made by the Dubbo community over the past year, covering both community and framework evolution, and look forward to future plans (roadmap) for the Dubbo community and framework. Community building is a very important aspect of promoting Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s healthy and sustainable development. We need to maintain positive interactions within the community, have active contributors, and engage in constructive discussions. Over the past year, the entire Dubbo community has made significant progress in this regard. In terms of framework evolution, we primarily released 6 feature versions from 2.7.0 to 2.7.5, covering various aspects including programming models, protocols, service governance, and performance optimization. In addition to released features, we also explored deeply into areas such as Dubbo 3.0 protocol, service introspection, and cloud-native directions. Support for these areas will be crucial for Dubbo&amp;rsquo;s future work, and we hope to share more detailed thoughts and plans through this article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meet Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/01/26/meet-dubbo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2019/01/26/meet-dubbo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a programmer with a Dubbo obsession.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo has accompanied me throughout my coding career for a short time in various ways. Not long ago, I was elected as a &lt;code>Committer&lt;/code> through community voting. At that time, I posted a phrase on my social network, which encapsulated my journey from starting to use Dubbo, researching Dubbo, contributing to Dubbo, and finally becoming a &lt;code>Committer&lt;/code>, providing me with a unique source of internal joy: it’s particularly happy to see footprints in the process of growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fifth Dubbo Developer Salon Successfully Held in Hangzhou</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/12/10/the-fifth-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-hangzhou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/12/10/the-fifth-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-hangzhou/</guid><description>&lt;p>The fifth Dubbo Developer Salon was successfully held in Hangzhou,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guest speakers&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Li Ding: How to Participate in the Dubbo Open Source Community &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/how-to-involve-in-dubbo-community.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cao Shengli: Introduction and Demonstration of New Features in Dubbo 2.7 &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/dubbo-2.7-introduction.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tao Yang: Application Practice of Dubbo at Koala &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/dubbo-practice-in-netease-koala.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Xiao Ma Ge: Reimplementation of Dubbo + Nacos Service Governance &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/nacos-support-in-dubbo.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zhao Yihao: Sentinel: Traffic Guard for Distributed Services &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/sentinel-support-for-dubbo.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chen Zhixuan: When Dubbo Meets Arthas: Troubleshooting Practice &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201812%40hangzhou/troubleshooting-dubbo-with-arthas.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>How to Prepare Apache Release</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-prepare-apache-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/09/02/how-to-prepare-apache-release/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-apache-release-content-and-processes">Understanding Apache Release Content and Processes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In general, the Source Release is the focus of Apache and is essential for the release; the Binary Release is optional. Dubbo can choose whether to publish a binary package to the Apache repository or release it to the Maven Central Repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please refer to the following links for more about ASF&amp;rsquo;s release guidelines:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/release-publishing">Apache Release Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/release.html">Apache Release Policy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/publishing-maven-artifacts.html">Maven Release Info&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="preparing-local-build-environment">Preparing Local Build Environment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mainly includes signing tools and Maven repository authentication preparations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 4th Dubbo Developer Salon Held in Chengdu on August 26</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/26/the-4th-dubbo-developer-salon-held-in-chengdu-on-august-26/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/08/26/the-4th-dubbo-developer-salon-held-in-chengdu-on-august-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/meetup-chengdu/all-hands.webp">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-depth-communication-with-users">In-depth Communication with Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On August 26, from 10:00 to 12:00, we invited four companies: Truck Alliance, Yuntu Jin Control, former BBD, and Feiyu Star, to participate in face-to-face discussions with open-source enthusiasts and heavy users. According to participant feedback, many questions about Dubbo were answered, especially regarding how to contribute to the community and the value points brought by donating code. We hope to engage more deeply in the Dubbo community and activities in the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Third Dubbo Developer Salon Held Successfully in Shenzhen</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/30/the-third-dubbo-developer-salon-held-successfully-in-shenzhen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/07/30/the-third-dubbo-developer-salon-held-successfully-in-shenzhen/</guid><description>&lt;p>The third Dubbo Developer Salon was successfully held in Shenzhen, with over 2,000 developers registering, more than 700 participants on-site, and a total of 17,000 online views guided by Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Tianchi, Yunqi Community, and Daka Talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speakers&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chen Zhixuan: The Current State of Dubbo Open Source and the Plan for 2.7&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kang Bin: The Microservices Journey of Lexin Group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lin Jialiang: Sentinel - The All-Round Traffic Sentinel for Enterprise Users&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Second Dubbo Developer Salon Successfully Held in Shanghai</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/06/23/the-second-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-shanghai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/06/23/the-second-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-shanghai/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Second Dubbo Developer Salon was successfully held in Shanghai, with over 700 developers registered and 300+ participants on site. The online live broadcast, guided by Alibaba Cloud Tianchi, Yunqi Community, and Daka Shuo, reached over 10,000 views.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speakers and PPT:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zhu Yong: The Current State and Future Plans of Dubbo (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-status-and-roadmap.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Xiao Ma Ge: Practical Experiences and Reflections on the Road to Dubbo Cloud Native (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-cloud-native-practices-and-thoughts.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guo Ping: Nacos - Contributing to the Dubbo Ecosystem, Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s Open Source Plans for the Registration Center and Configuration Center (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/nacos-open-source-initiative.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pan Zhiwei: Application Scenarios of Dubbo in the Internet Finance Industry (Chinese) &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/blob/master/slides/meetup/201806%40Shanghai/dubbo-practices-on-internet-finance-industries.pdf">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The First Dubbo Developer Salon Successfully Held in Beijing</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/12/the-first-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-beijing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/12/the-first-dubbo-developer-salon-successfully-held-in-beijing/</guid><description>&lt;p>The First Dubbo Developer Salon was successfully held in Beijing, with over 400 developers participating. This is a great start!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The speakers and topics are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Luo Yi: The Current Status and Future Planning of Dubbo &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/dubbo-present-and-future.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Liu Jun: The Fourth Ali Middleware Performance Challenge &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/introduction-to-4th-aliware-performance-challenge.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chen Zhi Xuan: Quickly Building Microservices with Dubbo and Spring Boot &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/quickly-building-microservice-with-dubbo-and-springboot.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wang Xin: Sharing the Service-Oriented Practice Journey of Dubbo and Weidian &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/meetup/201805%40Beijing/dubbo-and-weidian's-practice-on-microservice-architecture.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>ApacheCon NA Conference Agenda Published</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/02/apachecon-na-conference-agenda-published/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/05/02/apachecon-na-conference-agenda-published/</guid><description>&lt;p>Luo Yi/Liu Jun will give a talk titled &amp;ldquo;Introducing Apache Dubbo (Incubating): What is Dubbo and How it Works&amp;rdquo; at the ApacheCon conference held in Montreal. Please click &lt;a href="https://apachecon.dukecon.org/acna/2018/#/scheduledEvent/b8db9dc580d85853f">here&lt;/a> to view the conference agenda, and register &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/apachecon-north-america-2018-registration-43200327342">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2018 Projects Announced at Google Summer of Code</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/25/2018-projects-announced-at-google-summer-of-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/25/2018-projects-announced-at-google-summer-of-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the Google Summer of Code, 2018 projects were announced, and Raghu Reddy&amp;rsquo;s project &amp;ldquo;Apache Dubbo extends support for serial protocols&amp;rdquo; was &lt;a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/projects/#4747840161579008">accepted&lt;/a>! Congratulations to him!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publishing Dubbo Admin Images on DockerHub</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/23/publishing-dubbo-admin-images-on-dockerhub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/23/publishing-dubbo-admin-images-on-dockerhub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dubbo Admin is the service governance center for Dubbo, providing many features such as service governance and configuration management needed for daily operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dubbo Admin includes both front-end and back-end code. If users need to download the source code and compile it themselves, it will take some time. This experience is not ideal, especially for users who wish to quickly research and try Dubbo Admin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Docker is an open-source application container engine that allows developers to package applications and their dependencies into a portable image. There is a strong demand in the community for a Dubbo Admin image. Docker maintains a public repository, DockerHub, which also has many domestic mirrors, allowing for faster access. Publishing the Dubbo Admin image to DockerHub is a good choice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dubbo Roadmap Revealed at QCon Beijing 2018</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/22/dubbo-roadmap-revealed-at-qcon-beijing-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/04/22/dubbo-roadmap-revealed-at-qcon-beijing-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ro Yi delivered a keynote speech on the current status and future plans of Dubbo at QCon Beijing 2018. For more details, please check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/dubbo/awesome-dubbo/raw/master/slides/qcon2018/dubbo-present-and-future.pdf">slides&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Contribute to the Dubbo Community</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/03/11/how-to-contribute-to-the-dubbo-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/blog/2018/03/11/how-to-contribute-to-the-dubbo-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="img" src="https://dubbo.apache.org/imgs/blog/involve-dubbo/head.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article was first shared at the Apache Dubbo meetup in Chengdu, where the topic was discussed for the first time. It&amp;rsquo;s not that we lack better topics; rather, we believe this topic is crucial and even suggest it should be covered in every meetup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of you are familiar with the development history of Dubbo. Dubbo was open-sourced on GitHub in 2011 and, for several years, was not maintained due to various reasons. It was restarted by Alibaba in July last year and donated to Apache on February 16, 2018.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>