<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1 - Registry on Apache Dubbo</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/</link><description>Recent content in 1 - Registry on Apache Dubbo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1-1 - Address Illegal</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/1/</guid><description>This log can be ignored, service version or grouping mismatch. Appears only in the zookeeper registry, this check has been removed in version 3.1.7.
possible reason The service.group configured on the Provider side does not match the reference.group configured on the Consumer side (that is, the configuration of the service group). The service.version configured on the Provider side does not match the reference.version configured on the Consumer side (that is, the configuration of the service version).</description></item><item><title>1-3 - URL destruction failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/3/</guid><description>Possible Reason When FrameworkExecutorRepository is destroyed, calling CacheableFailbackRegistry.evictURLCache will cause the destruction to fail and generate an error code.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps See also the Configuration Items Reference Manual</description></item><item><title>1-4 - Empty address</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/4/</guid><description>Possible Reason Errors 1-4 in registry.integration.RegistryDirectory are caused by the null invokerUrls in the refreshInvoker process, which can be ignored. The 1-4 errors in registry.support.CacheableFailbackRegistry may be caused by the mismatch between consumer and provider, and the &amp;ldquo;null protection&amp;rdquo; is turned off. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Make sure that the service group configurations on the Provider and Consumer side correspond. Make sure that the service version configurations on the Provider and Consumer side correspond.</description></item><item><title>1-5 - URL received without any parameters</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/5/</guid><description>Possible Reason When calling CacheableFailbackRegistry.toUrlsWithoutEmpty, if there is a provider in Collection&amp;lt;String&amp;gt;providers that does not have any parameters, the URL without any parameters will be received.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error is an internal error of Dubbo. If you encounter it, you can create an Issue on github and provide the error information and steps to reproduce it. We will help you solve the problem.
see also Dubbo Community</description></item><item><title>1-6 - Error clearing URL cache</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/6/</guid><description>Possible Reason An error while clearing the url cache in CacheableFailbackRegistry.RemovalTask will trigger an error in clearing the URL cache.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error is an internal error of Dubbo, if you encounter it, you can create issues on github and provide the error information and steps to reproduce, we will help you solve the problem.
see also Dubbo Community</description></item><item><title>1-7 - Notification registration event failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/7/</guid><description>Possible Reason When applied to related platforms based on the xDS protocol, when metadata is updated, consumers need to be notified. If a consumer is offline, the notification will fail and the listener of the corresponding consumer will be removed. Troubleshooting and resolution steps see also Registration Center - Configuration Item Reference Manual</description></item><item><title>1-8 - Unregister (unsubscribe) address failed on destroy</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/8/</guid><description>Possible Reason An error may occur when the consumer logs out or unsubscribes due to the downtime of the registration center. It may be that the corresponding provider has not been released successfully. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the registration center is running normally. Check whether the provider is released successfully. Check whether the provider’s registry-related parameters such as registry config-center metadata-report are configured correctly. see also Configuration item reference manual</description></item><item><title>1-9 - Failed to read and write registry service cache</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/9/</guid><description>Possible Reason Multiple Dubbo processes (or other Java processes) use the same cache file. Due to the file system permission problem of the directory where the cache file is located, reading and writing fails. The value of dubbo.registry.file is entered incorrectly. Accidentally specify two registries to use the same file store. Hint: If dubbo.registry.file is not specified, the registry service cache path defaults to the ~/.dubbo directory (where ~ is the user&amp;rsquo;s HOME directory)</description></item><item><title>1-10 - Failed to read and write registry service cache</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/10/</guid><description>Possible Reason Multiple Dubbo processes use the same cache file. In the case of multiple registries, multiple registries are specified to use the same file storage. Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error often occurs with errors 1-9. Check whether multiple Dubbo processes use the same cache file or specify multiple registries to use the same cache file.
see also Reference Manual for Registry Configuration Items</description></item><item><title>1-11 - Registration service instance creation failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/11/</guid><description>Possible Reason It may be caused by Registry&amp;rsquo;s SPI/IOC configuration error.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error is an internal error of Dubbo. If you encounter it, you can create an Issue on github and provide the error information and steps to reproduce it. We will help you solve the problem.
see also Dubbo Community</description></item><item><title>1-12 - Instances of "Registry Service" have been destroyed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/12/</guid><description>Possible Reason During the graceful shutdown of Dubbo, unregister by calling destroyAll of AbstractRegistryFactory.
During the process of destroying the unexport of Registryprotocol, the getRegistry of AbstractRegistryFactory will be used to try to obtain the registry that has been destroyed, which leads to the destruction of all instances of the &amp;ldquo;registry service&amp;rdquo;.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps see also Configuration item reference manual</description></item><item><title>1-13 - Failed to execute task retry</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/13/</guid><description>Possible Reason The registry is offline. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check if the registry is working properly. Check whether the server where the registration center is located and its network are working normally.</description></item><item><title>1-14 - Dynamic configuration recognition failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/14/</guid><description>Possible Reason When using the service management function of dubbo admin for dynamic configuration, if the content or format of the configuration file is incorrect, the content of the dynamic configuration cannot be parsed, resulting in 1-14 errors.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Please check whether the content or format of the dynamic configuration file is correct.
See also Configuration Reference Manual</description></item><item><title>1-15 - Failed to destroy service</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/15/</guid><description>Possible Reason Throwing an exception while destroying all invokers in the RegistryDirectory may trigger errors 1-15.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error is an internal error of Dubbo. If you encounter it, you can create an Issue on github and provide the error information and steps to reproduce it. We will help you solve the problem.
See also Dubbo Community</description></item><item><title>1-16 - There are unsupported categories</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/16/</guid><description>Possible Reason When the registration center changes, the corresponding listener will be notified. If the category is illegal during notify, 1-16 errors will be generated.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps This error is an internal error of Dubbo. If you encounter it, you can create an Issue on github and provide the error information and steps to reproduce it. We will help you solve the problem.
Dubbo Community github</description></item><item><title>1-17 - Metadata Server Failure</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/17/</guid><description>Possible Reason It may be that there is a problem with the parameter configuration of metadata, especially metadataServiceProtocol and metadataServicePort.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether it occurs at the same time as 1-18 error, if it occurs at the same time, first try to solve 1-18 Check whether the metadataServicePort port number conflicts. If the ports configured by Provider and Consumer are in conflict at the same time, a 1-17 error will be generated.</description></item><item><title>1-18 - metadata service port not provided</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/18/</guid><description>Possible Reason It may be that metadataType is in local mode, and metadataServicePort is configured incorrectly.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the metadataType attribute value on the Provider side. Check whether the configuration of metadataServicePort on the Provider side is correct, and pay special attention to whether there is any conflict with other application ports. see also Configuration item reference manual</description></item><item><title>1-19 - K8S monitoring exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/19/</guid><description>Possible Reason K8S custom resource type, the configuration has been modified or removed by the container. The K8S container is disconnected from the service. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the custom resource type is correctly configured. For syntax, please refer to the official documentation of K8S. Check whether the network is normal or the port mapping is correct.</description></item><item><title>1-20 - K8S Pod does not exist</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/20/</guid><description>Possible Reason Pods may not exist or have been removed by containers.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-21 - K8S No Service Available</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/21/</guid><description>Possible Reason The current service is not loaded correctly. The configured Pod does not exist in the current instance service. Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-22 - K8S configuration address error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/22/</guid><description>Possible Reason The K8S url is configured incorrectly and cannot be accessed normally.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the K8S url configuration information to ensure that the port mapping can also be accessed normally.</description></item><item><title>1-23 - Unable to download files via url</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/23/</guid><description>Possible Reason The url mapping file does not exist. The URL cannot be connected. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the url mapping file exists. Whether it can be accessed normally through a browser or other tools.</description></item><item><title>1-24 - ZK startup exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/24/</guid><description>Possible Reason There is an incompatibility between the zk server version and the client version, and the connection cannot be made. The zk service is not started normally or the firewall cannot provide external services. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Confirm that the client version is consistent with the server version. zk can start normally or provide normal external services. You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-25 - ZK destruction exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/25/</guid><description>Possible Reason The current instance has been destroyed. The network may be disconnected.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-26 - xDS certificate generation failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/26/</guid><description>Possible Reason The system may not support algorithms secp256r1 and RSA to generate certificates.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check if the operating system supports secp256r1 and RSA algorithms. Need to download the dll file or lib for</description></item><item><title>1-27 - K8S monitoring exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/27/</guid><description>Possible Reason The system may not support algorithms secp256r1 and RSA to generate certificates.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check if the operating system supports secp256r1 and RSA algorithms. Need to download the dll file or lib for</description></item><item><title>1-28 - xDS Stub Error</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/28/</guid><description>Possible Reason The current pod may be down.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-29 - xDS failed to read file</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/29/</guid><description>Possible Reason The network is disconnected or the target file is corrupted at this time.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Whether the network is normal. You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-30 - xDS request failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/30/</guid><description>Possible Reason Versions may be inconsistent or incompatible. Timeout while reading data. There is a problem with parameter configuration. Troubleshooting and resolution steps It can be adapted according to the introduction of the third-party official website. Check whether the timeout setting is too short or there is a problem on the server. Check whether the port mapping relationship is correct.</description></item><item><title>1-31 - xDS Response Failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/31/</guid><description>Possible Reason The client service has disconnected from the server. The server is unavailable or offline. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the server is offline or the network of the client is disconnected. Check whether the service on the server side is normal, and the interface request can be made through the network.</description></item><item><title>1-32 - xDS Channel initialization failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/32/</guid><description>Possible Reason Versions may be inconsistent or incompatible. Timeout while reading data. There is a problem with parameter configuration. Troubleshooting and resolution steps It can be adapted according to the introduction of the third-party official website. Check whether the timeout setting is too short or there is a problem on the server. Check whether the port mapping relationship is correct.</description></item><item><title>1-33 - xDS service discovery initialization failed</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/33/</guid><description>Possible Reason The address configuration of the registration center in xDS mode is wrong. The firewall and third-party protection software make it impossible to provide external connections. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the xDS configuration is correct and whether the Istio status is normal. Check the firewall configuration or use the ping command of cmd for basic detection.</description></item><item><title>1-34 - Error parsing xDS</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/34/</guid><description>Possible Reason There is an error in the xDS protocol content.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps The cause can be located according to the Endpoints List printed by the stack.</description></item><item><title>1-35 - ZK Anomaly</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/35/</guid><description>Possible Reason ZK cannot connect or the connection times out. The ZNode already exists at the time of creation. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether ZK configuration IP and port number are correct. Connection testing can be done using the third-party tool ZooInspector According to the stack reminder ZNode information, judge whether the current node can be cleaned up.</description></item><item><title>1-36 - Unknown exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/36/</guid><description>Possible Reason Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-37 - Nacos Anomaly</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/37/</guid><description>Possible Reason Nacos configuration information is not configured correctly.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the ip and port number configured for Nacos are correct. If the security authentication of Nacos is enabled, check whether the user name and password are configured correctly.</description></item><item><title>1-38 - Socket connection exception</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/38/</guid><description>Possible Reason Connection refused. The connection has been closed. Troubleshooting and resolution steps You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.log to analyze the stack information and locate it.</description></item><item><title>1-39 - Failed to fetch metadata</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/39/</guid><description>Possible Reason Metadata Center has been disconnected from App Service. The data in the metadata center may have been modified. Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the network communication is normal, you can use some simple cmd commands to detect, such as ping and so on. Connect and view content through third-party tools.</description></item><item><title>1-40 - Route waiting too long</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/40/</guid><description>Possible Reason The route calculation time is too long, so the address notification cannot wait for an appropriate time to update the address.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check the application QPS, if the QPS is very high, this is the expected log Check the implementation of custom routes, and check whether there are abnormal implementations, such as deadlocks, infinite loops, etc. You can use some third-party tools or jstack [PID] &amp;gt; jstack.</description></item><item><title>1-41 - Istio exceptions</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/41/</guid><description>Possible Reason Failed to fetch configuration file for istio
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Check whether the application is deployed in the Kubernetes Pod environment, currently does not support VM deployment</description></item><item><title>1-42 - Nacos has a low version service</title><link>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dubbo.apache.org/en/docs3-v2/java-sdk/faq/1/42/</guid><description>possible reason The Nacos registry has subscribed to an old version of the service, usually because the Dubbo version on the server side is lower than 2.7.3.
Troubleshooting and resolution steps Upgrade the server to the latest stable version.</description></item></channel></rss>